. >> GOOD AFTERNOON WELCOME TO
THE APRIL 21ST 2026 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. >> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? >> YES SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN NOT
PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY
DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER NOT PRESENT
SUPERVISOR SIR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT SUPERVISOR GENTLEMAN
PRESIDENT MANDOLIN PRESENT SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL
SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON PRESENT
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT YOU HAVE A
QUORUM. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK THE
SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMITA COLONY.
WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS
LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW
MATERIAL ONI HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM
LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE ROMITA ALUMNAE COMMUNITY AND BY
AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE? THE REASONS I ASK STATES OF
AMERICA TO STANDS ONE NATION UNDER HAVE TO JUSTICE FOR.
>> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. CAPTIVE TV TODAY THAT IS ESPECIALLY SUSAN'S SHOWS.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE OUR
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
YES, MR. PRESIDENT. >> THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
WELCOMES YOUR ATTENDANCE HERE IN PERSON AT THE BOARD'S
LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER ROOM TWO 52ND FLOOR OF CITY HALL.
WHEN YOU CAN'T BE HERE, THE PROCEEDING IS AIRING LIVE ON
S.F. GOV TV'S CHANNEL 26 OR LIVE STREAMING AT W W W DOT
S.F. GOP TV DAWG YOU MAY SUBMIT PUBLIC COMMENT IN WRITING BY
SENDING AN EMAIL TO POST THAT S.F. GOP TALK OR VIA U.S.
POSTAL SERVICE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
. ONE DOCTOR CALL TEAM BE GOOD LA
PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA 94102.
TO MAKE A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A FUTURE
MEETING WITH UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT
OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE PLEASE CONTACT THE
CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY
CALLING (415) 554-5184. FINALLY WE ARE IN RECEIPT OF
TWO MEMOS AS STATED LAST WEEK. SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUBMITTED A
MEMO DATED APRIL 7TH REQUESTING TO BE EXCUSED EACH WEEK BETWEEN
APRIL 7TH AND JUNE 30TH AND ON APRIL 20TH WE RECEIVED A MEMO
FROM SUPERVISOR CHAN REQUESTING TO BE EXCUSED FROM TODAY'S
MEETING. MR. PRESIDENT, THAT CONCLUDES
MY COMMUNICATION. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
MAY I HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSED SUPERVISORS CHAN AND FIELDER
FROM TODAY'S MEETING MOVED BY CHAN SECONDED BY WALTON.
COLLEAGUES, I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
WITHOUT OBJECTION. SUPERVISORS CHAN AND FIELDER
ARE EXCUSED. AND WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK,
LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF THE MEETING MINUTES.
>> TODAY WE ARE CONSIDERING THE APPROVAL OF THE MARCH 17TH,
2026 BOARD MEETING MINUTES. >> AND I HAVE A MOTION TO
APPROVE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED TO MOVED BY CHEN
SECONDED BY CHERYL. MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES SUPERVISOR SLATER SARDAR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR WANG WANG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR MANAGEMENT HI MANZO AND I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
EITHER NINE DAYS WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE
APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S
GO TO OUR CONSENT AGENDA PLEASE CALL ITEMS ONE THROUGH 14
TOGETHER ITEMS ONE THROUGH 14 ARE ON CONSENT.
THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED ROUTINE.
IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED
SEPARATELY. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
ITEMS ONE THROUGH 14 SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WANG WANG I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANAGEMENT HI
MANAGEMENT I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I THERE ARE NINE EYES
WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED
MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER 15. >> ITEM NUMBER 15 IS AN
ORDINANCE TO APPROVE THE AIRPORT AIRPORT SURVEILLANCE
TECHNOLOGY POLICY GOVERNING THE USE OF THE TRANSPORTATION
NETWORK COMPANY VIRTUAL VIRTUAL QUEUE TECHNOLOGY SUPERVISOR
MELGAR THANK YOU PRESIDENT AND THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND I
HAD THE OPPORTUNITY OR WAS VALEAN TOLD TO SUB IN FOR MY
COLLEAGUE SUPERVISOR FIELDER ON THE GAO COMMITTEE WHEN WE HEARD
THIS AND I HAD A LOT OF QUESTIONS BUT BECAUSE IT'S NOT
MY COMMITTEE I WAS JUST KIND OF SUBBING.
I ENDED UP, YOU KNOW, VOTING TO PASS IT IN LAST WEEK ON FIRST
READING YOU KNOW, THERE WERE SOME QUESTIONS THAT CAME UP
FROM FOLKS IN THE INDUSTRY AND I'VE ALSO HEARD FROM LABOR
THAT THERE THEY HAVE LOTS OF QUESTIONS ABOUT THE IMPACT THAT
THIS WILL HAVE ON MOSTLY DRIVERS.
SO I I'M GOING TO DO SOMETHING VERY UNUSUAL TO ASK THAT WE
SEND IT BACK TO COMMITTEE. I THINK, YOU KNOW, TECHNOLOGY
HAS THE POTENTIAL TO MAKE OUR LIVES BETTER AND EASIER AND IT
ALSO HAS A POTENTIAL TO BRING UP ISSUES SOME PROBLEMS THAT WE
HAVEN'T THOUGHT ABOUT AND I THINK THIS IS THE CASE FOR THIS
THERE ARE PRIVACY ISSUES UNDER THE CURRENT CLIMATE.
>> YOU KNOW, WE DO HAVE A LOT OF DRIVERS WHO ARE IMMIGRANTS.
WE THERE'S JUST THERE'S A LOT OF QUESTIONS THAT I HAVE ABOUT
HOW THIS IS GOING TO PLAY OUT IN REAL LIFE.
SO I AM GOING TO ASK THAT WE SEND THIS BACK TO COMMITTEE SO
THAT WE CAN THOROUGHLY VETTED AND THEN HEAR FROM EVERYONE AS
I REMEMBER WHEN WE HEARD THIS ITEM AT GAO THERE REALLY WASN'T
ANYONE WHO CAME AND BECAUSE SINCE THEN WE'VE HAD LOTS OF
QUESTIONS FROM FOLKS IN THE PUBLIC I DO THINK THAT PEOPLE
AT LEAST SHOULD HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY AT THEIR OTHER ASK
THOSE QUESTIONS DURING COMMITTEE AND TO GET ANSWERS
AND FOR US TO HAVE A PUBLIC VETTING OF ALL THE ISSUES.
SO I WILL MAKE A MOTION TO SEND THIS BACK TO COMMITTEE
SUPERVISOR MELGAR HAS MADE A MOTION TO REFER THIS BACK TO
COMMITTEE SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR WALTON.
ANY COMMENTS OR DISCUSSION? CAN WE TAKE THAT SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL? >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION
PASSES. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 16. >> ITEM NUMBER 16 IS AN
ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO
ESTABLISH THE FIRE CODE TECHNICAL ADVISORY COUNCIL TO
EVALUATE AND ADVISE ON THE CRITERIA AND TYPES OF EVIDENCE.
A FIRE MARSHAL SHOULD CONSIDER IN DETERMINING WHETHER TO
WAIVE, MODIFY OR DELAY CERTAIN COMPLIANCE REQUIREMENTS UNDER
THE FIRE CODE THAT CERTAIN EXISTING HIGH RISE RESIDENTIAL
BUILDINGS HAVE SPRINKLER SYSTEMS AND TO SET FORTH THE
MEMBERSHIP AND DUTIES OF THE FIRE CODE TECHNICAL ADVISORY
COUNCIL PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE SIDE OF ON ITEM 16
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON NO SUPERVISOR WANG WANG I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR BENJAMIN HI MADAM
AND I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I THERE ARE EIGHT EYES AND ONE
NO WITH SUPERVISOR WALTON VOTING NO THE ORDINANCE IS
FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL OUT A NUMBER 17.
>> ITEM NUMBER 17 IS AN ORDINANCE TO EXTEND FOR AN
ADDITIONAL FIVE YEARS THROUGH JULY 1ST 2031 THE DELEGATION OF
A OF AUTHORITY UNDER CHARTER SECTION 9.118 TO THE GENERAL
MANAGER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION TO
ENTER INTO GRANT AGREEMENTS UNDER THE SPARKS GREEN
INFRASTRUCTURE GRANT PROGRAM WITH TERMS OF UP TO 20 YEARS
AFTER THE PROJECT COMPLETION DATE AS DEFINED BY THE GRANT
AGREEMENTS PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THIS ITEM ON ITEM 17.
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WANG WANG I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANAGEMENT HI I'M
IN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I THERE ARE NINE EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION AND THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 18.
>> ITEM NUMBER 18 IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE
AND AUTHORIZE THE GENERAL MANAGER OF THE SFP SEE TO
EXECUTE A CONTRACT WITH ARCHER ENERGY SOLUTIONS LLC TO PROVIDE
AS NEEDED PROFESSIONAL SERVICES TO HERSHEY WATER AND POWER TO
MEET NORTH AMERICAN ELECTRIC RELIABILITY CORPORATION,
WESTERN ELECTRICITY COORDINATING COUNCIL CALIFORNIA
INDEPENDENT SYSTEM OPERATOR AND CALIFORNIA PUBLIC UTILITY
COMMISSION REGULATORY REQUIREMENTS FOR AN AMOUNT OF
11.6 MILLION WITH AN ANTICIPATED TIME FRAME FROM MAY
2026 THROUGH MAY 2031. >> I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS
ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED AND MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 19
AND 20 TOGETHER ITEMS 19 AND 20 ARE TWO RESOLUTION ESTABLISHING
APPROPRIATION LIMITS ITEM 19 ESTABLISHES THE APPROPRIATION
LIMIT OF 14.6 BILLION FOR FISCAL YEAR 2025 TO 2026
PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA CONSTITUTION ARTICLE 13 B DUE
TO THE ADDITION OF LOCAL NONRESIDENTIAL NEW CONSTRUCTION
AND THE PERCENT CHANGE IN POPULATION WITHIN THE SAN
FRANCISCO METROPOLITAN AREA FROM THE PREVIOUS YEAR FOR THE
PURPOSE OF COMPUTATION OF ITS APPROPRIATIONS LIMIT AND ITEM
20 IS A RESOLUTION TO ESTABLISH THE APPROPRIATIONS LIMIT FOR
SPECIAL TAX DISTRICTS AND INFRASTRUCTURE
REVITALIZATION AND FINANCING DISTRICTS FOR FISCAL YEARS 2025
THROUGH 2026 PURSUANT TO CALIFORNIA CONSTITUTION ARTICLE
13 B AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER 21. >> ITEM NUMBER 21 IS A
RESOLUTION TO RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE DEPARTMENT OF
ELECTIONS TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND FUNDS ALLOCATED BY THE
CALIFORNIA SECRETARY OF STATE IN AN AMOUNT APPROXIMATELY
416,000 TO FUND THE VOTING SYSTEM AN ELECTRIC ELECTION
MANAGEMENT SYSTEM REPLACEMENT FOR THE PERIOD OF JULY 1ST,
2025 THROUGH AUGUST 31ST 2026. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAME CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 22.
ITEM NUMBER 22 IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE THE AGREEMENT
BETWEEN THE PENINSULA CORRIDOR JOINT POWERS OR ITS MEMBER
AGENCIES REGARDING THE PENINSULA CORRIDOR JOINT JOINT
POWERS BOARD'S FINANCE FISCAL OBLIGATIONS TO CALIFORNIA
PUBLIC EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL OUT
A NUMBER 23 ITEM NUMBER 23 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE
ZONING MAP OF THE PLANNING CODE TO CHANGE THE HEIGHT AND BULK
DISTRICTS FOR THE ONE OAK STREET PROJECT TO INCREASE THE
ALLOWED HEIGHT FOR THE PODIUM OF THE BUILDING FROM THE
CURRENT BASE HEIGHT LIMIT OF 120FT TO 140FT.
TO AFFIRM THE SECRET DETERMINATION AND MAKE MAKE THE
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 24 AND 25 TOGETHER.
>> ITEMS 24 AND 25 ARE TWO RESOLUTIONS TO DETERMINE IF THE
LIQUOR LICENSES WILL SERVE THE PUBLIC CONVENIENCE OR NECESSITY
OF THE CITY ITEM 24 IS FOR A PERSON TO PERSON PREMISE TO
PREMISE TRANSFER OF A TYPE 21 ALSO GENERAL BEER WINE
AND DISTILLED SPIRITS LIQUOR LICENSE TO TAZA D'AMORE DOING
BUSINESS AS 20 OR MORE AT CAFE LOCATED AT 704TH STREET
AND ITEM 25 IS FOR PERSON TO PERSON PREMISE TO PREMISE
TRANSFER OF A TYPE 48 ON SALE GENERAL PUBLIC PREMISES BEER
WINE AND DISTILLED SPIRITS LIQUOR LICENSE TO 77 ASSET SALE
LLC DOING BUSINESSES BACH 77 LOCATED AT 77 CAMDEN DRIVE SAME
HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL OUT A NUMBER 26 ITEM NUMBER 26
IS A RESOLUTION TO AFFIRM THE IMPORTANCE OF KEEPING THE
INDEPENDENT CIVILIAN OVERSIGHT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
COMMISSION. SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL IT NUMBER SEVEN.
>> NUMBER 27 ITEM NUMBER 27 IS A MOTION TO APPROVE OF TO
APPOINT SUPERVISORS CHEYENNE CHEN TERM ENDING FEBRUARY 4TH,
2013 AS AN ALTERNATE MEMBER ON THE LOCAL AGENCY FORMATION
COMMISSION. >> COLLEAGUES CAN I HAVE A
MOTION TO EXCUSE SUPERVISOR CHEN FROM VOTING MOVED BY
WALTON SECONDED BY MAHMUD WITHOUT OBJECTION SUPERVISOR
CHEN IS EXCUSE MADAM CLERK CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
ITEM NUMBER 27 ON ITEM 27 SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I.
SUPERVISOR HUANG HUANG I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HI MANDOLIN
I SUPERVISE HER MELGAR MELGAR EITHER EIGHT EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED AND CONGRATULATE
AND SUPERVISOR CHEN MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR COMMITTEE
REPORT THE YES TO OUR COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEM 28 WAS CONSIDERED
BY THE GOVERNMENT AUDIT AND OVERSIGHT COMMITTEE AT A
REGULAR MEETING ON THURSDAY APRIL 16TH AND WAS RECOMMENDED
AS A COMMITTEE REPORT. IT IS A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE
SETTLEMENT OF AN LITIGATED CLAIMS ON BEHALF OF THE CITY
AND THE PEOPLE OF THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA AGAINST ASSOCIATED
PHARMACIES J.M. SMITH CORPORATION, LOUISIANA
WHOLESALE DRUG COMPANY MORRIS AND DIXON, NORTH CAROLINA
MUTUAL WHOLESALE DRUG COMPANY AND UNITED NATURAL FOODS FOR
ABATEMENT FUNDS IN THE RANGE OF 250,000 TO 350,000.
THESE CLAIMS RELATE TO SETTLING COMPANIES ALLEGEDLY IMPROPER
AND UNLAWFUL UNLAWFUL PRACTICES WHICH CONTRIBUTED TO THE
EPIDEMIC OF OPIOID ABUSE AND MISUSE AND CAUSED A PUBLIC
NUISANCE. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THIS
ITEM ON ITEM 28 SUPERVISOR SAUTER SARDAR I SUPERVISOR
CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WANG
WANG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMUD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MADAM AND I
GENTLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I THERE ARE NINE EYES
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 29 AND 30 TOGETHER ITEMS 29
THROUGH 31 WERE CONSIDERED BY THE RULES COMMITTEE AT A
REGULAR MEETING ON APRIL A MONDAY APRIL 20TH AND WERE
RECOMMENDED AS COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEMS 29 AND 30 BEING
CALLED ARE TO ORDINANCES ESTABLISHING ENTERTAINMENT
ZONES IN ITEM 29 AMENDS ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO CREATE
THE GLENN PARK ENTERTAINMENT ZONE AND MAKE THE APPROPRIATE
FINDINGS. AN ITEM 30 IS AN ORDINANCE TO
AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO CREATE THE UPPER FILLMORE
ENTERTAINMENT ZONE AND MAKE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
LET'S TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES ARE PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 31.
>> ITEM NUMBER 31 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ESTABLISH THE PACIFIC ISLANDER
CULTURAL DISTRICT IN AND AROUND THE VISITATION VALLEY
AND SUNNYDALE NEIGHBORHOODS TO REQUIRE THE MAYOR'S OFFICE OF
HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT TO SUBMIT WRITTEN
REPORTS AND RECOMMENDATIONS DESCRIBING THE CULTURAL
ATTRIBUTES OF THE DISTRICT AND PROPOSING STRATEGIES TO
ACKNOWLEDGE AND PRESERVE THE CULTURAL LEGACY OF THE DISTRICT
AND MAKING APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU FOR PRESIDENT.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO ADD MYSELF AS A CO-SPONSOR.
>> THANK YOU AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES PASSED.
>> OKAY, ADMIRAL ALLEN WONG I WOULD LIKE TO ADD MYSELF TO
THIS ORDINANCE AS WELL GOING ONCE GOING TWICE.
>> OKAY THEN WITHOUT TWO NEW CO-SPONSORS.
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS
PASSED ON FIRST READING AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO A
ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS. >> FIRST UP ON ROLL CALL FOR
INTRODUCTIONS IS SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUBMIT THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL COLLEAGUES TODAY I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE A
HEARING ON THE CITY'S VICIOUS AND DANGEROUS DOGS UNIT.
>> FOR OVER A YEAR THIS UNIT HAS NOT MET.
>> THERE IS NO PROFESSIONAL WHO CAN ADMINISTER THESE HEARINGS
AND AT THE SAME TIME DOG BITES ARE ON THE RISE.
THIS HEARING WILL FOCUS ON DELIVERING A PLAN TO RESTART
THOSE HEARINGS A HEARING FOR HEARINGS.
>> FIRST BY FILLING THE VACANT HEARING OFFICER POSITION
AND SECOND BY ENGAGING WITH CERTIFIED DOG BEHAVIORISTS TO
ENSURE OUR PROCESS IS INFORMED BY THE LATEST RESEARCH AND DOG
BEHAVIOR ADVOCATES IN THE DOG COMMUNITY NAMELY THOSE AT S.F.
DOG AS WELL AS THE POLICE DEPARTMENT, THE DEPARTMENT OF
POLICE ACCOUNTABILITY AND MORE HAVE BEEN WORKING TOGETHER TO
ENSURE THAT WE PROMOTE RESPONSIBLE SAFE DOG OWNERSHIP
IN THE CITY. AT THE END OF THE DAY THIS IS
ABOUT PUBLIC SAFETY IS ABOUT CHILDREN, IT'S ABOUT DOGS, IT'S
ABOUT OWNERS AND IT'S ABOUT ALL OF US.
SO I WANT TO THANK MY EARLY CO SPONSORS SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD
AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN FOR SUPPORTING THIS HEARING AND WE
HOPE THAT WE GET THE VICIOUS AND DANGEROUS DOG UNIT BACK TO
BEING A NATIONAL EXAMPLE IN ADDRESSING DANGEROUS DOG
BEHAVIOR, PROTECTING PEOPLE AND DOGS.
>> LET'S NOT FORGET THAT FROM AGGRESSIVE INCIDENTS IN PARKS
IN OUR STREETS. THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND THE
REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR SHERYL SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
I SUBMIT BUT I WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK AFTER SUPERVISOR MELGAR
SUPERVISOR WONG COLLEAGUES I WOULD LIKE TO TAKE A MOMENT
TODAY TO RECOGNIZE IN MEMORIAM THE LIFE OF MY GRANDMOTHER ON
TAKING PART IN WHO WE LOVINGLY CALLED PAUL PAUL SHE WAS BORN
IN THE EARLY 1920S IN MACAO AND LIVED THROUGH BOTH TIMES OF
PROSPERITY AND PROFOUND HARDSHIP HER FAMILY OWNED
BUSINESSES BUT BUT HER EARLY YEARS WERE ALSO SHAPED BY THE
REALITIES OF WAR. SHE EXPERIENCED LOSS
AND UNCERTAINTY THAT MOST OF US CAN ONLY IMAGINE.
AND THROUGH IT ALL SHE CARRIED A QUIET STRENGTH AND RESILIENCE
THAT DEFINED HER LIFE. SHE PURSUED EDUCATION WITH THE
HOPE OF BECOMING A TRADITIONAL CHINESE DOCTOR DRIVEN BY A
DESIRE TO CARE FOR OTHERS THAT SPURRED STAYED WITH HER AS SHE
PASSED DOWN TO OUR FAMILY KNOWLEDGE OF CHINESE CULTURE,
TRADITIONS AND VALUES. SHE LATER MARRIED AND RAISED
HER CHILDREN, DEDICATING HERSELF TO HER FAMILY WHILE SHE
ONCE CONSIDERED BECOMING A BUDDHIST MONK, SHE CHOSE TO
REMAIN WITH HER LOVED ONES AND INSTEAD LIVED A DEEPLY
SPIRITUAL LIFE OFFERING PRAYERS, GUIDANCE AND COMFORT
TO THOSE AROUND HER ESPECIALLY IN MOMENTS OF LOSS.
TO ME SHE WAS NOT JUST MY GRANDMOTHER.
SHE WAS MY TEACHER, MY PROTECTOR AND A STEADY PRESENCE
IN MY LIFE IN THE SUNSET WHERE SO MANY FAMILIES LIKE MINE
BUILT THEIR LIVES. HER VALUES CONTINUE TO GUIDE
HOW I SHOW UP FOR MY COMMUNITY EVERY DAY.
HER LIFE REMINDS ME THAT STRENGTH IS OFTEN QUIET
AND THAT THE GREATEST IMPACT WE CAN HAVE IS IN HOW WE CARE FOR
THE PEOPLE AROUND US. THANK YOU COLLEAGUES FOR
ALLOWING ME TO TAKE THIS MOMENT TO HONOR THEIR ASSESSMENT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WONG SUPERVISOR CHEN
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSI THANK YOU AND SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD. >> COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M
INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION TO RECOGNIZE APRIL AS AUTISM
AWARENESS MONTH WITH A FOCUS ON MOVING BEYOND AWARENESS TOWARDS
REAL INCLUSION AND TANGIBLE APPRECIATION.
THIS IS PERSONAL FOR ME BUT IT IS ALSO GROUNDED IN WHAT WE'RE
SEEING ACROSS OUR CITY RIGHT NOW IN 2026.
PROGRAMS LIKE YOUTH ACHIEVE AND BRIDGES FROM SCHOOL TO WORK
ARE HELPING YOUNG PEOPLE TRANSITION FROM HIGH SCHOOL
INTO EMPLOYMENT, HIGHER EDUCATION AND LONG TERM
INDEPENDENCE. THESE ARE THE KINDS OF PROGRAMS
THAT DELIVER REAL OUTCOMES AND NOT JUST GOOD INTENTIONS.
WE'VE MADE PROGRESS OVER THE PAST DECADE.
THE CONVERSATION HAS SHIFTED FROM AWARENESS TO ACCEPTANCE
AND INCREASINGLY TOWARDS INCLUSION.
>> BUT THE DATA IS CLEAR AUTISM IS A SPECTRUM AND IT PRESENTS
DIFFERENTLY ACROSS GENDER RACE AND CULTURE.
FOR TOO LONG ENTIRE COMMUNITIES WERE OVERLOOKED OR
MISDIAGNOSED. TODAY WE'RE SEEING MORE PEOPLE
ESPECIALLY ADULTS GETTING DIAGNOSED LATER IN LIFE
AND FINALLY UNDERSTANDING THEIR EXPERIENCES.
AND AS SOMEONE WHO WAS DIAGNOSED LATER IN LIFE, THAT
PERSPECTIVE INFORMS HOW I APPROACH THIS WORK AND WHY IT
MATTERS. NATIONALLY, AUTISM AFFECTS
ABOUT 1 IN 36 CHILDREN AND DIAGNOSES CONTINUE TO RISE
HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO. WE DEMAND FOR SERVICES
CONTINUES TO GROW FASTER THAN OUR SYSTEMS ARE BUILT TO
HANDLE. AT THE SAME TIME WE'RE
OPERATING IN A TIGHT BUDGET ENVIRONMENT AND THAT MAKES THE
PRIORITIZATION EVEN MORE IMPORTANT.
I BELIEVE THIS IS AN AREA WHERE WE NEED TO STAY FOCUSED
AND WHERE POSSIBLE DOUBLE DOWN THESE INVESTMENTS DIRECTLY
IMPACT PEOPLE'S ABILITY TO LEARN, WORK AND LIVE
INDEPENDENTLY. WE ALSO NEED TO RECOGNIZE HOW
CRITICAL CITY INFRASTRUCTURE IS BECAUSE SERVICES LIKE THE SAN
FRANCISCO MUNICIPAL TRANSPORTATION AUTHORITY AGENCY
ARE ESSENTIAL FOR MANY NEURODIVERGENT RESIDENTS.
WHAT MAY SEEM LIKE A SMALL SERVICE CHANGE WHEN WE DISCUSS
THINGS LIKE SERVICE CUTS INVOLVES ROUTE ADJUSTMENT
DELAYED LINES WHICH CAN HAVE A MAJOR IMPACT ON SOMEONE WHO
DEPENDS ON CONSISTENCY AND ROUTINE.
SO WHEN WE TALK ABOUT BUDGETS AND WHEN WE TALK ABOUT SERVICE
LEVELS, WE NEED TO REMEMBER THESE DECISIONS SHOW UP
IN PEOPLE'S DAILY LIVES IN VERY REAL WAYS.
>> THIS RESOLUTION ACCORDINGLY RECOGNIZES ORGANIZATIONS DOING
CRITICAL WORK ON THE GROUND INCLUDING FELTON INSTITUTE, THE
BAY AREA AUTISM COLLECTIVE AND THE ARC SAN FRANCISCO.
I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE PARTNERSHIP OF CITY DEPARTMENTS
AND LEADERS INCLUDING THE SAN FRANCISCO DEPARTMENT OF
CHILDREN, YOUTH AND THEIR FAMILIES OFFICE ON DISABILITY
AND THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT.
THANK YOU TO MY COLLEAGUE SHEILA SHERALD DORSEY, SADR,
WONG MELGAR AND WALTON FOR YOUR EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP OVER THIS
LAST YEAR. I'VE HEARD FROM SO MANY
FAMILIES AND PARENTS FROM INDIVIDUALS ACROSS THE
NEURODIVERGENT COMMUNITY. THIS STORIES MAKE IT CLEAR THAT
WE HAVE MORE WORK TO DO. SO THIS RESOLUTION IS ABOUT
RECOGNITION BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY ABOUT ALIGNING OUR
POLICIES AND INVESTMENTS WITH THE REALITIES PEOPLE ARE LIVING
EVERY DAY. THE GOAL IS SIMPLE MAKE SURE
EVERY RESIDENT HAS THE SUPPORT THEY NEED TO SUCCEED AND THRIVE
IN THIS CITY. THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND TO
HAVE YOUR SUPPORT ON THIS RESOLUTION.
SECOND, I WOULD LIKE TO INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION FOR THE
CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO CELEBRATING
ARAB-AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH. ARAB-AMERICANS HAVE MADE
PROFOUND AND LASTING CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE CULTURAL,
SOCIAL AND ECONOMIC POLITICAL LANDSCAPE OF THIS COUNTRY.
ENRICHING THE NATION'S HISTORY WITH THE RESILIENCE
AND INNOVATION AND CREATIVITY ARAB-AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH
OBSERVED IN THE MONTH OF APRIL OFFERS A MEANINGFUL OPPORTUNITY
TO HONOR THE DIVERSE CULTURES AND TRADITIONS OF
ARAB-AMERICANS FROM 22 COUNTRIES AND TO PROMOTE
UNDERSTANDING OF THEIR CONTINUED IMPACT ON AMERICAN
SOCIETY. THE ARAB-AMERICAN COMMUNITY
HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO HAS A RICH AND PROUD HISTORY OF
CONTRIBUTING TO THE CITY'S DIVERSE IDENTITY WITH
INDIVIDUALS AND FAMILIES FROM A VARIETY OF ARAB NATIONS
INCLUDING LEBANON, SYRIA, PALESTINE, EGYPT, IRAQ, JORDAN,
YEMEN AND OTHERS. BUILDING HOMES, BUSINESSES
AND COMMUNITIES IN THE CITY FOR GENERATIONS.
DISTRICT FIVE WHERE I REPRESENT IS HOME TO ONE OF THOSE
THRIVING ARAB-AMERICAN COMMUNITIES PARTICULARLY IN THE
TENDERLOIN WHERE WE'VE HAD IMMIGRATION AND REFUGEES FROM
YEMEN FOR SO MANY YEARS. THOSE RESIDENTS COME FROM A
ARRAY OF BACKGROUNDS AND TRADITIONS AND HAVE MADE
SIGNIFICANT CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR CITY'S SO SMALL BUSINESSES
CULTURE AND SOCIETAL FABRIC. AND SO THIS RESOLUTION
ACKNOWLEDGES AND RECOGNIZES THOSE ARAB-AMERICANS WHO
CONTINUE TO ADVOCATE FOR SOCIAL JUSTICE, EQUITY
AND REPRESENTATION WORKING TO ENSURE FUTURE GENERATIONS
THRIVE AND FEEL A SENSE OF BELONGING IN THE CITY AND HELP
SHAPED LIKE COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS LIKE THE ARAB
RESOURCE AND ORGANIZING CENTER. WE ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE
ARAB-AMERICAN OWNED BUSINESSES AND THE NEIGHBORHOOD BUSINESS
ALLIANCE THAT REPRESENT ARAB GROCERS AND OTHER ARAB BUSINESS
CHAMBERS OF COMMERCE THAT ENRICH THE LOCAL ECONOMY WHILE
ALSO SERVING AS SPACES FOR CULTURAL EXCHANGE, COMMUNITY
GATHERING AND EDUCATION. NOW MORE THAN EVER IT'S
IMPORTANT TO UPLIFT OUR DIVERSE COMMUNITIES AND TO FIGHT
AGAINST DISCRIMINATION, XENOPHOBIA AND HATE AND AFFIRM
OUR DEDICATION TO SUPPORTING ARAB-AMERICANS AND ALL
MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES AND ACHIEVING EQUALITY
AND JUSTICE. THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN.
>> I WILL SUBMIT MY LEGISLATION.
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. >> SUPERVISOR MELGAR I'M SORRY
I'M RIGHT. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
AND COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM THRILLED TO INTRODUCE A
RESOLUTION COMMENDING THE WORKFORCE OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
PUBLIC WORKS DEPARTMENT AND DECLARE APRIL 20TH THROUGH
APRIL 24TH 2026 AS PUBLIC WORKS WEEK IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF
SAN FRANCISCO. PUBLIC WORKS IS ONE OF THE
LARGEST AND OLDEST DEPARTMENTS IN THE CITY.
>> THEY WORK TIRELESSLY TO ENSURE THAT EACH DAY EVERY
NEIGHBORHOOD IN SAN FRANCISCO IS SAFE, ACCESSIBLE, CLEAN,
FUNCTIONAL AND GREEN. >> THE BACKBONE OF THIS
DEPARTMENT IS THAT 1400 EMPLOYEES WHO SACRIFICE THEIR
DAYS AND NIGHTS TO HELP THE PUBLIC OPERATE AND HAVE THESE
SERVICES 24 SEVEN. THEY ARE A DEDICATED GROUP OF
FOLKS WHO WORK DILIGENTLY TO RESPOND TO ANY CITY EMERGENCY
THAT COMES UP WHETHER THAT'S REMOVING HAZARDS, DEALING WITH
STORMS, PAVING THE STREETS, DESIGNING PUBLIC SPACES, ROAD
REPAIRS OR IMPROVING ACCESSIBILITY AND SO MUCH MORE.
>> THE PUBLIC WORKS REAL PEOPLE REAL WORK CAMPAIGN REFLECTS THE
PEOPLE THAT WORK BEHIND THE SCENES EVERY DAY TO SERVE THE
COMMUNITY IN MEANINGFUL WAYS. >> THEY ALSO HELP HOST
INCLUSIVE PROGRAMS LIKE MONTHLY NEIGHBORHOOD BEAUTIFICATION
DAYS WHICH WE'VE ALL PARTICIPATED IN.
GRAFFITI WATCH IN ADAPTIVE STREET.
JUST THIS PAST MARCH, PUBLIC WORKS ANNUAL SAN FRANCISCO
ARBOR DAY FAIR PLANTED 100 TREES ACROSS A HANDFUL OF
NEIGHBORHOODS IN SAN FRANCISCO .
COMMUNITY EVENTS LIKE THESE WOULDN'T BE POSSIBLE WITHOUT
THE COMMITTED WORKFORCE OF DPW. >> WE ARE GRATEFUL TO DIRECTOR
SHORT AND ALL OF HER STAFF FOR EVERYTHING THAT PUBLIC WORKS
CONTRIBUTES TO SAN FRANCISCO AND WE ALL ARE EXCITED TO
CONTRIBUTE TO CONTINUE COLLABORATING WITH THEIR
AMAZING TEAM IN 2026. ALSO COLLEAGUES AT TODAY IT IS
WITH GREAT SADNESS THAT I JOIN MY COLLEAGUE SUPERVISOR SHYANNE
CHEN AND SHARMAN WALTON IN REQUESTING AN IN MEMORIAM ON
BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE BOARD FOR THE LATE GREAT BELOVED REVEREND
ROLAND GORDON ALSO KNOWN TO US AS REDD G OF THE INGLESIDE
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH WHO PASSED AWAY UNEXPECTEDLY LAST WEEK.
>> JUST LAST YEAR WE CELEBRATED REGGIE'S 81ST BIRTHDAY
AND DECLARED FEBRUARY 13TH REVEREND ROLAND GORDON DAY
IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
REGGIE IS A LOCAL ICON AND TREASURE WHO HAS LEFT A
LASTING IMPACT ON EVERYONE THAT HE HAS MET.
HIS LEGACY REPRESENTS THE BEST OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> REGGIE WAS BORN IN GREENWOOD, MISSISSIPPI
BEFORE MOVING WITH HIS FAMILY TO GARY, INDIANA, WHERE HE WAS
A CAPTAIN AND STAR PLAYER ON HIS HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL TEAM
. IT WAS THERE THAT HE MET MARY
JANE, THE GIRL WHO WOULD ONE DAY BECOME HIS WIFE OF OVER 50
YEARS BUILDING UPON A CHILDHOOD FRIENDSHIP INTO A LIFELONG
PARTNERSHIP BUILT ON THE FOUNDATION OF SERVICE
AND MINISTRY. >> REGGIE BEGAN HIS MINISTRY
FIRST AS A STUDENT PASTOR AT INGLESIDE PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH
IN SAN FRANCISCO ON OCEAN AVENUE.
AFTER COMPLETING SEMINARY AND COMPLETING HIS MASTER OF
DIVINITY DEGREE, HE WAS ORDAINED AS INGLESIDE
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH AS A FULL TIME PASTOR IN 1983.
THE CHURCH WAS MORE THAN JUST A PLACE OF WORSHIP FOR REGGIE BUT
A PLACE TO BUILD COMMUNITY HEALING AND EMPOWERMENT.
>> SEEING THE CHURCHES IN MAN'S POTENTIAL, REGGIE ORGANIZED THE
INGLESIDE CHURCH BASKETBALL LEAGUE INSIDE THE CHURCH'S
GYMNASIUM PROVIDING A POSITIVE SPACE FOR LOCAL YOUTH TO LEARN
AND PLAY. REGGIE HAD A PROFOUND BELIEF
THAT BLACK CHILDREN NEEDED TO SEE POSITIVE EMPOWERING IMAGES
OF PEOPLE WHO LOOKED LIKE THEM .
FROM THIS VISION HE CREATED THE GREAT WALL OF WITNESSES A
MASSIVE COLLAGE WITH IMAGES THAT ADORN THE WALLS OF THE
CHURCHES, GYM AND LOBBY CELEBRATING BLACK LEADERSHIP
AND BLACK EXCELLENCE. IT IS RECOGNIZED AS THE LARGEST
BLACK AMERICAN COLLAGE IN THE WORLD AND IT IS ALSO OFFICIALLY
A HISTORIC LANDMARK IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
HIS LIFE'S WORK HAS ALWAYS REVOLVED AROUND BUILDING UP
YOUNG PEOPLE TO ACHIEVE THEIR GREATEST POTENTIAL AND MOREOVER
TO DEVELOP YOUNG LEADERS TO BECOME MENTORS.
MANY WHO GREW UP WITHOUT A FATHER FOUND A GUIDE AND A
FATHER FIGURE IN REGGIE. HE FOUNDED THE THAD BROWN
ACADEMY FOR BOYS IN AFTER SCHOOL PROGRAMS SERVING YOUNG
BLACK BOYS IN GRADES FIVE THROUGH EIGHT.
>> THROUGH THIS PROGRAM HE PROVIDED MENTORSHIP LEADERSHIP
TRAINING COMPUTER LITERACY, DISCIPLINE AND ENCOURAGEMENT
HELPING SHAPE NOT ONLY THEIR EDUCATION BUT THEIR CHARACTER
AND FUTURE POSSIBILITIES. REGGIE POSITED HIS CHURCH AS A
NEXUS IN THE OCEAN VIEW, SETTING ASIDE COMMUNITY
FACILITATING LOCAL ORGANIZING AND PROVIDING MEETING SPACE FOR
COMMUNITY EVENTS INVITING RENOWNED ARTISTS TO ADDRESS THE
COMMUNITY AND REHABILITATING WHAT IS NOW THE CITY COLLEGE
STATION. THEN THE DILAPIDATED FEEL
AND LOOP INTO A BEAUTIFUL GREEN SPACE CALLED UNITY PLAZA.
HE WAS A CONNECTOR THAT UNIFIED FAITH LEADERS ACROSS MANY
DENOMINATIONS AND SUPPORTED STRENGTHENING TIES BETWEEN THE
BLACK AND ASIAN COMMUNITIES. OUR ANNUAL LUNAR NEW YEAR
CELEBRATION FOR DISTRICT SEVEN AND 11 GOT ITS START AT
INGLESIDE PRESBYTERIAN AS A COLLABORATION BETWEEN MY
PREDECESSOR FORMER PRESIDENT SEVEN SUPERVISOR NORMAN YEE
AND REGGIE TO RECOGNIZE THE UNITY AND DEEP TIES BETWEEN THE
BLACK AND ASIAN COMMUNITIES OF DISTRICT SEVEN AND 11.
REVEREND GORDON HAS BEEN WIDELY RECOGNIZED FOR HIS OUTSTANDING
DEDICATION TO HIS CHURCH AND COMMUNITY.
RECEIVING THE 1995 CASH GLENN AWARD FOR COMMUNITY SERVICE THE
2003 DISTINGUISHED ALUMNI AWARD FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO
THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY. THE 2004 ALUMNI MARRIED AWARD
FROM HIS ALMA MATER, BALDWIN WALLACE COLLEGE AND THE 2023
NATIONAL JACQUELINE KENNEDY ONASSIS AWARD FOR OUTSTANDING
PUBLIC SERVICE BENEFITING LOCAL COMMUNITIES.
I WILL FOREVER BE GRATEFUL TO HAVE KNOWN RICHIE AND THE WORLD
PEACE AFFIRMATION CARDS HE WOULD GIVE ME AND DROP BY MY
OFFICE ON A WEEKLY BASIS THAT HE WOULD HAND OUT TO EVERYONE
WHICH WAS INSPIRED BY THE PEACE PRAYER OF SAINT FRANCIS OF
ASSISI A CONSTANT REMINDER THAT WE CAN ALL BE INSTRUMENTS OF
PEACE. I WANT TO SHARE MY DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO HIS DEVOTED WIFE MARY JEAN GORDON LOVINGLY
REFERRED IN OUR COMMUNITY AS FIRST LADY GORDON HIS DAUGHTERS
PHYLLIS BRYANT AND GAIL YOUNG. HIS GRANDDAUGHTERS CHINA GORDON
BRIANA BRYANT AND LONDON YOUNG AND HIS GREAT GRANDCHILDREN
ZION MCGEEVER OCEAN BASS AND BOSTON.
HE'S ALSO SURVIVED BY HIS SIBLINGS PAULINE ROBERT GORDON,
STANLEY GORDON STELLA GORDON AND RICHARD GORDON HIS
GODCHILDREN JAMAAL MA BRIGHT JESSICA MYBURGH SHAHEEN SANCHEZ
DAVID BENTON, DEREK BENNETT AND MARY JANE.
ALONG WITH A HOST OF NIECES NEPHEWS, RELATIVES, CHERISHED
FRIENDS AND GENERATIONS AND GENERATIONS OF YOUNG PEOPLE
FROM OCEAN BOOMER SAID INGLESIDE THAT HE TOUCHED
AND MENTORED REGGIE'S MESSAGE WAS PURE AND SIMPLE LOVE IS THE
ANSWER AND THROUGH EVERY LIFE HE TOUCHED EVERY YOUNG PERSON
HE GUIDED EVERY IMAGE HE CREATED IN EVERY WORD HE
PREACHED. THAT ANSWER CONTINUES TO LIVE
ON. THANK YOU, REGGIE, FOR
EVERYTHING YOU GAVE OUR COMMUNITY THROUGH THE
PRESIDENT. I WOULD LOVE IT IF WE COULD
CLOSE TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF REGGIE.
ON BEHALF OF THE FULL BOARD OF SUPERVISORS AND THE REST I'LL
SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
SUPERVISOR CHAD THANK YOU, CLARK MADAM CLERK.
I WANT TO EXPRESS MY DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO REFUGEES FAMILY
AS WELL AND ALSO TO THE CONGREGATION AND COMMUNITY.
ALTHOUGH I ONLY HAD THE PRIVILEGE TO GET TO KNOW REV
REVEREND JERRY OVER THE LAST FEW YEARS HE'S ALWAYS EMBRACED
ME VERY WARMLY AND OFFERED HIS UNCONDITIONAL SUPPORT.
REVEREND G HELPED TO KICK OFF AND HOST THE FIRST LUNAR NEW
YEAR CELEBRATE NATION ON OCEAN AVENUE IN 2019 AND SINCE THEN
HAS CONTINUED IT TO HOST A PRESS EVENT AT THE INGLESIDE
PETS BY TERRY AND STREAM. THE GYM WAS SUCH AN IMPORTANT
SPACE TO REVEREND G. AS A FORMER ATHLETIC HE SAW HOW
THE SPACE COULD BRING NEIGHBORHOOD YOUTH AND FAMILY
TOGETHER. >> THE GYM KNOWN AS FELLOWSHIP
HALL IS THE LEGACY. REVEREND G COVERED THE GYM WITH
WITH LOTS OF IMAGE FROM THE FLOOR TO CEILING FEATURING
FACES OF ATHLETICS, POLITICIAN ENTERTAINERS
AND AFRICAN-AMERICAN LEADERS. >> REVEREND G HAS DONE SO MUCH
FOR THE COMMUNITY VERY, VERY LITTLE RESOURCES.
>> HIS CHURCH PROVIDES YOUTH PROGRAMING AND ASSISTANCE TO
OUR COMMUNITY'S MOST VULNERABLE THROUGH FOOD PROGRAMS
IN BUILDING COMMUNITY. REVEREND G WAS COMMITTED TO
BUILD ACROSS RACIAL SOLIDARITY TO NATURE TO NURTURE BLACK
AND ASIAN UNITY AND ALSO TO ADVOCATE FOR RESTORATIVE
JUSTICE FOR OUR COMMUNITY. PEOPLE OF COLOR'S.
>> FOR THE LAST FIVE DECADES REVEREND G HAS BEEN AN
INSPIRATION AND BELOVED A MEMBER OF OUR AND MY COMMUNITY.
MAY WE CONTINUE TO HONOR AND TO CELEBRATE HIS MEMORY.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR WALTON. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
AND I JUST WANT TO SAY I SAY MY SINCERE CONDOLENCES TO REVEREND
G'S FAMILY AND COMMUNITY AND I JUST WANT TO SAY A FEW WORDS TO
ADD TO SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND SUPERVISOR CHIN.
REVEREND G WAS MORE THAN JUST A MEMBER OF THE CLERGY.
HE WAS A MAN COMMITTED TO BETTERING THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY
AROUND HIM. HE WAS RARE IN THE FACT THAT HE
COULD RELATE TO YOUNG PEOPLE AS WELL AS ELDERS.
HE HAD THE ABILITY TO CONNECT WITH EVERYONE ACROSS ALL
NEIGHBORHOODS IN SAN FRANCISCO .
AND HE HAD A GENUINELY GENTLE SPIRIT.
WHERE MOST PEOPLE WOULD NOT ALLOW OTHERS TO USE THEIR
FACILITIES OR THEIR CONGREGATIONS FOR EVENTS
AND CEREMONIES. HE OPENED HIS DOORS
AND WELCOMED ALL. BUT I'M GOING TO APPRECIATE THE
MOST IS THE FACT THAT HE COULD PROVIDE ADVICE AND MENTORSHIP
BUT ALLOW YOU TO RECEIVE THE INFORMATION AND MOVE
ACCORDINGLY. REGGIE WOULD TRULY BE MISSED BY
ALL COMMUNITIES ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO AND I AM PROUD TO SAY
A FEW WORDS IN HIS HONOR TODAY. ONE OF A KIND TO DESCRIBE HIM
IS REALLY AN UNDERSTATEMENT. HIS CONNECTION WITH YOUNG
PEOPLE AND THE TUTELAGE HE PROVIDED THEM IS UNMATCHED.
HIS WORK WITH OTHER FAITH LEADERS TO BRING PEOPLE
TOGETHER IS PART OF WHAT MADE HIM SO BELOVED.
I WANT TO SAY CONDOLENCES AGAIN AND THANK YOU SO MUCH
SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR PRESENTING THIS THIS AFTERNOON
. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR.
SEE NO OTHER NAMES ON THE ROSTER.
>> MR. PRESIDENT, THAT CONCLUDES ROLL CALL FOR
INTRODUCTIONS. >> ALL RIGHT, MADAM CLERK,
LOGISTICALLY I BELIEVE SUPERVISOR MELGAR HAS MADE A
MOTION THAT THE IN MEMORIAM BE ON BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE BOARD
AND A SECOND FOR THAT. NO, NO, NO SECOND IS REQUIRED
AND WE TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> GREAT. MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR
2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER. >> OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER IS A
RECOGNITION ACCOMMODATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND FIRST UP DISTRICT FOR
SUPERVISOR WONG. OKAY.
MAY I GET MY YEAH. >> COME UP.
>> TODAY I'M HONORED TO RECOGNIZE YOU SEE S.F. ALS
CENTER AND DR. CATHERINE LOHMAN HEARST FOR THEIR EXTRAORDINARY
LEADERSHIP IN THE CARE AND TREATMENT OF PEOPLE LIVING
WITH ALS ALSO KNOWN AS LOU GEHRIG'S DISEASE.
ALS IS A PROGRESSIVE AND FATAL NEUROLOGICAL DISEASE FOR
FAMILIES FACING INHERITED RISK. THE BURDEN IS NOT ONLY THE
DISEASE ITSELF BUT ALSO THE FEAR, UNCERTAINTY AND DELAY
THAT CAN COME LONG BEFORE A DIAGNOSIS.
FOR TOO MANY FAMILIES THAT HAS MEANT WAITING FAR TOO LONG FOR
ANSWERS, TREATMENT AND SUPPORT .
>> THAT IS WHY UCSF'S LEADERSHIP IN THIS FIELD
MATTERS SO DEEPLY UNDER DR. LOWMAN HER DIRECTION.
THE UCSF ALS CENTER HAS HELPED LEAD THE WAY IN ADVANCING MORE
PROACTIVE, COMPASSIONATE AND RESEARCH DRIVEN CARE FOR
PATIENTS AND FAMILIES CONFRONTING THIS DEVASTATING
DISEASE. DR. LOWMAN KURTH HAS DEDICATED
HER CAREER TO IMPROVING CARE FOR PEOPLE OF ALS WHILE ALSO
ADVANCING RESEARCH INTO THE EARLY SIGNS AND GENETIC RISK
FACTORS OF THE DISEASE. EXPANDING ACCESS TO CLINICAL
TRIALS AND HELPING DEEPEN OUR UNDERSTANDING OF THE
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN ALS AND FRONTOTEMPORAL DEMENTIA.
JUST AS IMPORTANTLY, UCSF HAS BEEN A PIONEER IN RECOGNIZING
THE NEEDS OF PEOPLE AND FAMILIES WHO ARE AT RISK OF
INHERITED ALS. BY HELPING ESTABLISH A MORE
FORWARD LOOKING MODEL OF CARE, THE UCSF ALS CENTER IS SHOWING
THAT PRECISION AND PREVENTATIVE MEDICINE CAN AND SHOULD PLAY A
ROLE IN HOW WE SUPPORT THESE FAMILIES.
THIS WORK SENDS A POWERFUL MESSAGE TO SAN FRANCISCO
AND BEYOND THAT PEOPLE FACING ALS AND THOSE LIVING WITH THE
RISK OF IT DESERVE NOT ONLY WORLD CLASS TREATMENT BUT ALSO
COMPASSION, URGENCY AND HOPE. ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. I'M PROUD TO COMMEND THE UCSF,
L.A. LAW CENTER AND DR. KATHRYN LOWMAN HEALTH FOR THEIR
PIONEERING LEADERSHIP, THEIR COMPASSIONATE CARE AND THEIR
COMMITMENT TO IMPROVING THE LIVES OF PATIENTS AND FAMILIES
AFFECTED BY ALS. >> AND I'LL HAND IT OVER TO
THEM. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THIS IS AN INCREDIBLE HONOR FOR OUR CENTER AND I'D LIKE TO
ACKNOWLEDGE THE PEOPLE THAT ARE WITH ME TODAY.
I HAVE MEMBERS OF OUR ALS CLINIC AT UCSF.
WE ALSO HAVE MEMBERS FROM THE END THE LEGACY ORGANIZERS ASIAN
AND PEOPLE WHO ARE AT RISK FOR DEVELOPING ALS AND FTD.
THIS HONOR IS PARTICULARLY MEANINGFUL BECAUSE THIS IS A
GROUP THAT OF PEOPLE THAT REALLY HAD TO SUFFER IN SILENCE
. THERE WAS NOT A PLACE WHERE
PEOPLE COULD GO IF THEY WERE AT RISK FOR DEVELOPING ALS OR FTD
TO YOU, YOU KNOW, SUPPORT EACH OTHER AND ALSO EVEN TO BE ABLE
TO GET MEDICAL CARE. IT'S VERY HARD WHEN SOMEONE IS
AT RISK BUT DOES NOT HAVE NEUROLOGICAL SYMPTOMS YET TO
SEE A NEUROLOGIST AND I CREDIT JAMIE FONG A GENETICS COUNSELOR
IN OUR GROUP WHO INSISTED THAT BEFORE ANY PATIENT OBTAIN
TESTING FOR EITHER ALS OR FTD THEY WERE EVALUATED BY A
NEUROLOGIST AND A PLAN OF CARE ESTABLISHED TO FOLLOW THEM
AFTER THEY TESTED POSITIVE. AND SO I'M VERY GRATEFUL FOR
THE LEGACY ORGANIZATION ESTABLISHED BY GENE SWINDLER
WHICH ALLOWS PEOPLE WHO ARE AT RISK TO COME TOGETHER FOR
SUPPORT FOR EDUCATION AND IMPORTANTLY TO PARTICIPATE
IN RESEARCH SO THAT WE CAN THEY CAN TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THERAPIES
THAT WE KNOW WORK BEST WHEN DELIVERED AS EARLY AS POSSIBLE
IN THESE DISEASES. >> SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
THIS HONOR. >> JUST VERY BRIEFLY I WANT TO
SAY THANK YOU SO MUCH TO DR. LOWMAN HER THANK YOU TO
SUPERVISOR WANG AND THE ENTIRE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FOR
ALLOWING THIS A UNIQUE SERVICE WHICH SHOULD NOT BE UNIQUE TO
BE ESTABLISHED IN SAN FRANCISCO FOR THE SAKE OF OUR LIKE A
SINGLE PHOTO FOR STARTERS. BUT I REGRET OKAY LET'S DO A
SINGLE YEAH I'LL TAKE 74. I DON'T KNOW IF IT WAS OKAY.
I'LL DO OKAY. OKAY.
>> NEXT UP WE HAVE DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
>> COLLEAGUES IN HONOR OF EARTH DAY, I'M PROUD TO RECOGNIZE A
GROUP OF NEIGHBORS FROM HAZE VALLEY.
>> CAN WE HAVE THE HAYES VALLEY NEIGHBORHOOD CLEANUP CREW COME
UP TO THE PODIUM? >> THIS CREW HAS TURNED A
SIMPLE IDEA INTO SOMETHING TRULY IMPACTFUL.
A WEEKLY ACT OF CIVIC CARE, ENVIRONMENTAL STEWARDSHIP
AND COMMUNITY BUILDING. THE NEIGHBORHOOD CLEANUP CREW
IS PART OF THE BROADER REFUSE, REFUSE AND CIVIC JOY FOUR
NETWORK ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO. >> THIS EFFORT BUILDS ON
EARLIER WORK BY THE HAYES VALLEY NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATION
SCREENING COMMITTEE WHICH HOSTED MONTHLY CLEANUPS AT
PATRICIA'S GREEN FROM THAT FOUNDATION, A NEW WEEKLY EFFORT
LAUNCHED IN MAY 2023 BRINGING TOGETHER CIVIC JOY FUND
REFEREE, SURFACE AND LOCAL COMMUNITY LEADERS.
IT STARTED WITH JUST 13 PARTICIPANTS.
SINCE THEN IT HAS GROWN INTO A CONSISTENT AND THRIVING
TRADITION. TODAY ABOUT 50 VOLUNTEERS SHOW
UP EVERY WEEK. SOMETIMES MORE THAN 80
AND THERE'S NO SIGNS OF THEM SLOWING DOWN.
IN TOTAL THE GROUP HAS CONTRIBUTED TO MORE THAN 150
CLEANUPS, REMOVING OVER 5700 BAGS OF TRASH AND MORE THAN
74,000 GALLONS OF WASTE FROM OUR STREETS.
BUT THE REAL STORY HERE ISN'T JUST THE NUMBERS.
EVERY SATURDAY MORNING NEIGHBORS GATHER AT GAMBIT
LOUNGE HOSTED BY EDWARD AND CHRISTINE CALHOUN.
FROM THERE, VOLUNTEERS ARE WELCOMED, ORGANIZED AND SENT
OUT BY A DEDICATED TEAM OF CAPTAINS, MANY OF WHICH ARE
HERE TODAY. THOSE CAPTAINS ARE DAVID
ROBINSON, DAN SPAETH, CHRISTINE CALHOUN, CRYSTAL SHU,
CHRISTOPHE PETERS, JAY SMITH. CARL TING WILDE.
A.J. HARRIS NAPOLI AND EDWARD CALHOUN.
WHAT THEY'VE BUILT GOES BEYOND A CLEANUP.
IT'S A COMMUNITY. PEOPLE WHO FIRST SHOWED UP AS
STRANGERS WHO NOW RETURN WEEK AFTER WEEK AS FRIENDS FAMILIES
THAT BRING THEIR CHILDREN. >> STUDENTS THAT JOIN ALONGSIDE
LONGTIME RESIDENTS EVEN VISITORS FROM AROUND THE WORLD
HAVE TAKEN PART. >> BUT ONE MOMENT REALLY
CAPTURES THE SPIRIT THAT HAPPENED RECENTLY ON A DAY OF
HEAVY RAIN WHEN THE CLEANUP WAS CALLED OFF, ABOUT 25 VOLUNTEERS
SHOWED UP ANYWAY AND INSISTED ON GOING OUT.
THAT KIND OF COMMITMENT SAYS EVERYTHING.
>> THERE'S SUCH A STRONG SENSE OF MUTUAL SUPPORT WHERE LOCAL
MERCHANTS OFFER DISCOUNTS AND PERKS TO THE VOLUNTEERS.
THE GAMBIT LOUNGE HAS GROWN ALONGSIDE THIS EFFORT HOSTING
WEEKLY GATHERINGS AND EVEN INSPIRING EVENTS LIKE VOLUNTEER
LED TRIVIA NIGHTS. AT ITS CORE THIS IS WHAT EARTH
DAY IS ABOUT PEOPLE COMING TOGETHER, TAKING RESPONSIBILITY
FOR THEIR ENVIRONMENT AND BUILDING SOMETHING
MEANINGFUL THROUGH SMALL CONSISTENT ACTIONS.
TO ALL THE CAPTAINS AND VOLUNTEERS.
THANK YOU. YOU'VE MADE HAYES VALLEY
CLEANER, MORE CONNECTED AND MORE VIBRANT.
AND YOU'VE SET AN EXAMPLE FOR WHAT A COMMUNITY CAN LOOK LIKE
ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU.
ASIDE FROM THE FACT THAT YOU SAID ALMOST EVERYTHING I WAS
GOING TO SAY. SO I'M GOING TO SHORTCHANGE
THIS A LITTLE BIT WITH A BUNCH OF THANK YOU'S.
THANK YOU, VINCE. AND REFUSE REFUSE.
WHAT BEGAN AS A SIMPLE ACT OF COMMUNITY SERVICE HAS GROWN
INTO AN UNSTOPPABLE MOVEMENT WORKING TOWARD A SHARED GOAL
FOR EVERYONE'S BENEFIT. IT'S VERY POWERFUL.
>> THANK YOU, MANNY, FOR BELIEVING IN THIS
AND SUPPORTING IT THROUGH THE CIVIC JOY FUND.
THANK YOU. HAYES VALLEY NEIGHBORHOOD
ASSOCIATION FOR LEADING WITH CARE AND COMMITMENT.
THANK YOU TO EDWARD AND CHRISTINE AT GAMBIT LOUNGE
FOR GIVING US THIS PLACE TOGETHER.
THANK YOU TO ALL OF OUR CO-CAPTAINS DAVID J.
CRYSTAL, RJ CARL. AND ALSO I'D LIKE TO THANK JOE
MALONEY WHO WAS SITTING IN THE BACK AS THE BOARD PRESIDENT OF
HB AND WE WORKED VERY CLOSELY TOGETHER.
AND THANK YOU SAN FRANCISCO FOR RECOGNIZING THE COMMITMENT OF
THIS COMMUNITY AND MAKING OUR CITY A CLEANER AND BRIGHTER
PLACE TO BE. LET'S GO BUILD SOME MORE
COMMUNITY. >> THANK YOU.
>> ALL RIGHT
. >> NEXT UP DISTRICT SIX
SUPERVISOR DORSEY. >> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT
RANDLEMAN. COLLEAGUES, IT IS MY HONOR TO
RECOGNIZE SAMA PILIPINAS AS IT CELEBRATES TEN YEARS OF
LEADERSHIP IN ADVANCING PRESERVING AND CELEBRATING
FILIPINO CULTURE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
I'D LIKE TO WELCOME RAQUEL, RODAN DIAZ AND OTHERS UP TO THE
LECTERN. >> DR..
OKAY, COME ON. ALL RIGHT.
>> COME ON. OKAY.
WELL SO SINCE IT'S ORIGINAL DESIGNATION IN 2016 AS THE
CITY'S FILIPINO CULTURAL HERITAGE DISTRICT AND SOONER
SOON AFTER AT THE STATE LEVEL SOMA PILIPINAS HAS LED THE
CULTURAL DISTRICTS MOVEMENT IN SAN FRANCISCO AND ACROSS
CALIFORNIA VIRTUALLY ALL OF IT UNDER RAQUEL'S LEADERSHIP.
TODAY WE ARE THEY ARE THEY ARE LAUNCHING DECATUR A YEAR LONG
CELEBRATION OF A DECADE OF COMMUNITY ARTS ACTIVISM
AND CULTURAL IMPACT. AS DISTRICT SIX SUPERVISOR I AM
BLESSED TO REPRESENT A SOUTH OF MARKET NEIGHBORHOOD THAT
LARGELY COMPRISED IS THE SOMA PILIPINAS CULTURAL DISTRICT.
AND WHILE MY DISTRICT IS PROUDLY THE CULTURAL HOME OF
SAN FRANCISCO'S FILIPINO COMMUNITY, IT HAS BEEN A LONG
STANDING PRACTICE WITH MY DISTRICT 11 COLLEAGUE FIRST
SUPERVISOR ASHA SAFAI AND NOW SUPERVISOR CHEYENNE CHEN TO
ALWAYS ALSO ACKNOWLEDGE AND CELEBRATE DISTRICT 11 FOR
BEING THE HOME OF THE LARGEST FILIPINO POPULATION IN SAN
FRANCISCO. SO YOU GOT TO SUPERVISE OUR
DISTRICTS. NOW I THINK SOME OF YOU HAVE
PROBABLY HEARD ME AT VARIOUS EVENTS TALK SOMETIMES ABOUT WHY
I HAVE A SPECIAL AFFECTION FOR THIS COMMUNITY.
TO ANYONE WHO WONDERS WHY AN IRISH ITALIAN KID WHO MOVED
HERE NEARLY 40 YEARS AGO FROM BOSTON WOULD HAVE A CONNECTION
TO THE FILIPINO COMMUNITY. IF YOU GUESS THE CATHOLIC
CHURCH YOU'RE ARE 100% RIGHT WHEN CHURCHES REOPENED AFTER
COVID I STARTED GOING TO SAINT PATRICK'S CHURCH BOTH BECAUSE
IT WAS MORE CONVENIENT THAN THE CHURCH I WAS GOING TO AND ALSO
BECAUSE ST PATRICK'S HAS THE BEST CANDLES IN CHRISTENDOM.
WHAT WHAT I CAME TO DISCOVER AT THAT PREDOMINANTLY FILIPINO
PARISH WAS AN INCREDIBLY SPECIAL AND VIBRANT FAITH
COMMUNITY. AND I HAVE TRULY COME TO
CHERISH HOW THE FILIPINO CULTURAL VALUES OF KAPWA INFORM
AND ANIMATE A NEW FOR ME MY MY OWN UNDERSTANDING OF CATHOLIC
TEACHING ESPECIALLY AS IT APPLIES TO COMMUNITY AND TO
SOCIAL JUSTICE. THOSE CULTURAL VALUES ARE NOBLY
CELEBRATED BY SALMA PILIPINAS AND I AM INCREDIBLY GRATEFUL TO
HAVE HAD A FRONT ROW SEAT TO THE WORK THAT RAQUEL AND HER
ENTIRE TEAM AND THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY HAVE DONE OVER THESE
LAST FOUR YEARS AS SUPERVISOR SALMA PILIPINAS HAS GROWN A
VIBRANT CULTURAL ECOSYSTEM DRIVEN BY ARTISTS, SMALL
BUSINESSES, COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS WORKING TOGETHER
TO PROTECT CULTURE, SUPPORT RESIDENTS AND STRENGTHEN
NEIGHBORHOOD IDENTITY. AS OUR CITY STRUGGLED IN ITS
ECONOMIC RECOVERY AFTER THE COVID PANDEMIC, I WAS SO PROUD
TO SEE HOW SALMA PILIPINAS STEPPED UP AND SUPPORTED WITH
SMALL BUSINESS OPENINGS AND CULTURAL ACTIVATIONS AT A
TIME WHEN THE CITY WAS REALLY STRUGGLING.
IT WAS JUST INSPIRING TO SEE OUR CULTURAL DISTRICTS
ESPECIALLY SALMA PILIPINAS REALLY STEP UP AND PUT OUR
COMMUNITY THERE. ALL OF OUR CITY AND ITS
ECONOMIC RECOVERY ON THEIR BACKS.
IT'S REALLY SOMETHING THAT I THINK WHEN THE HISTORY OF THIS
AREA IS WRITTEN YOU'RE GOING TO BE A REAL HERO OF THAT.
IN ADDITION TO THEIR LONG STANDING AUNTIE TO DISPLACEMENT
EFFORTS SALMA PILIPINAS CHESS STRATEGIES AND COMMUNITY
OUTREACH HAVE BEEN CRITICAL IN STABILIZING VULNERABLE
COMMUNITIES AT AN INCREDIBLY FRAUGHT TIME AND I THINK THE
KNOW YOUR RIGHTS TRAINING FOR IMMIGRANTS IS JUST ONE OF THE
MOST IMPORTANT EXAMPLES FOR THAT AND I'M PROUD TO HAVE
TAKEN PART IN THAT AT ST PATRICK'S AS WELL.
THEY'VE ALSO TRANSFORMED THE PUBLIC REALM THROUGH MURALS,
CROSSWALKS AND CULTURAL EVENTS LIKE THE PAROLE LANTERN
FESTIVAL. I UNDERSTAND SANTA WHAT SAT THE
ACTUAL SANTA WAS THERE A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO DRAWING THOUSANDS
AND CONTRIBUTING MORE TO OUR DOWNTOWN RECOVERY.
THEIR DEVELOPMENT OF A CULTURAL DISTRICT MASTER PLAN CONTINUES
TO SET THE STANDARD FOR CULTURAL DISTRICTS CITYWIDE
AND I ESPECIALLY APPRECIATE THEIR LEADERSHIP IN EFFORTS
LIKE THE LANDMARKING OF THE MALL WHICH IS JUST A BLOCK FROM
WHERE I LIVE WHERE I OFTEN VISIT J T RESTAURANT AND TO
PROTESTS AND CELEBRATE BIRTHDAYS GET MY HAIRCUT AND SO
MUCH MORE. MY OFFICE IS REALLY PROUD
EVERYBODY IN MY OFFICE IS PROUD TO BE IN SUPPORT OF YOUR WORK
INCLUDING THE FUTURE DISTRICT GATEWAY AT FOLSOM AND RUSH RUSS
LIKE SO MANY SELMA RESIDENTS, WE ARE ALL LOOKING FORWARD SO
MUCH TO WHAT LIES AHEAD FROM THIS AMAZING ORGANIZATION TO
RAQUEL AND EVERYBODY FROM SALMA PILIPINAS AND EVERYONE FROM THE
COMMUNITY. CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR FIRST
DECADE MILESTONE AND TO THE MEANINGFUL COMMUNITY DRIVEN
WORK YOU DO FOR DISTRICT SIX AND FOR ALL OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> THANK YOU FOR DOING THIS. AND YOU HAVE COLLEAGUES WHO SEE
WHO WANT TO COUPLE ACCORDING TO YOUR MARKS SUPERVISOR JEN THANK
YOU FOR PRESENT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR
HONORING MUCH FILIPINAS TODAY I ALSO WANT TO EXPRESS MY DEEP
APPRECIATION FOR YOUR WORK BECAUSE THE LARGEST POPULATION
OF FILIPINOS IN THE CITY LIVE IN DISTRICT 11.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR PARTNERSHIP WITH THE FILIPINO
COMMUNITY CENTER BALBOA HIGH SCHOOL LONGFELLOW ELEMENTARY TO
BRING FILIPINO CULTURE TO THE SCHOOLS.
THE INTERPRETATION IN CLASSES WITH SOME KIM AND CITY COLLEGE
CREATED MORE CERTIFIED FILIPINO LANGUAGE SPEAKERS TO MEET THE
GROWING NEED FOR CULTURALLY COMPETENT SERVICES.
THANK YOU FOR BUILDING WORKER SOLIDARITY THROUGH PARTNERSHIP
WITH LABOR AND JOBS WITH JUSTICE TO CONTACT KNOW YOUR
RIGHTS TRAININGS AND TEACHING THE HISTORY OF FILIPINO
DISPLACEMENT REACHING OVER 500 CITY WORKERS AT DPW AND MO
EXCEED MTA AND PLANNING YOUR ADVOCACY FOR BUILDING
AFFORDABLE HOUSING FOR FAMILIES AND YOUR WORK THAT YOU DO WITH
API COUNCIL. IT'S CRITICAL FOR CULTURAL
PRESERVATION AND COMMUNITY STABILIZATION.
THESE ARE JUST A FEW HIGHLIGHT OF YOUR INCREDIBLE WORK.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND THANK YOU FOR
ADVOCATING FOR OUR MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> THANK YOU. THE CASE SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, PRESIDENT MENDHAM.
AND I JUST WANT TO JUST SAY TO RAQUEL I HAVE SO MUCH RESPECT
FOR YOUR ORGANIZATION AND THE WORK THAT YOU DO AND IT'S NOT
JUST BECAUSE IT'S WOMEN LED BUT IT'S REALLY A TESTAMENT TO THE
RESILIENCY AND THE STAYING POWER OF YOUR ENTIRE COMMUNITY
. MUCH LIKE THE BLACK COMMUNITY,
THE FILIPINO POPULATION HAS SHIFTED HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
BUT YOU HAVE CONTINUE TO MAKE SURE THAT THERE WAS A STRONG
PRESENCE AND THE PRESENCE OF THE FELLOW COMMUNITY FILIPINO
COMMUNITY IS SEEN. AND SO I JUST WANT TO SAY THANK
YOU FOR CONTINUING TO REP YOUR COMMUNITY.
AND CONGRATULATIONS TO SOME OF FILIPINAS.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY AND SUPERVISOR CHEN
AND SUPERVISOR WALTON FOR YOUR WORDS AND EVERYONE HERE AT THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS EACH OF YOU HAVE SHOWN TREMENDOUS
SUPPORT FOR SIMPLE HAPPINESS AND THE FILIPINO COMMUNITY
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND WE THANK YOU.
WELL, I WAS GOING TO ASK EVERYONE TO STAND BUT AS YOU
CAN SEE WE HAVE HERE COMMUNITY LEADERS AND PARTNERS WHO HAVE
JOINED US IN RECEIVING THIS COMMENDATION.
WE SHARE THIS ORDER TODAY WITH THE RESIDENTS, SMALL BUSINESSES
AND COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS WHICH MAKE THE FILIPINO
CULTURAL HERITAGE DISTRICT A LIVING AND THRIVING COMMUNITY.
WE'RE GRATEFUL TO BE JOINED HERE TODAY WITH SOME OF THE
COMMUNITY PILLARS AND UNSUNG HEROES.
THERE ARE MANY, MANY MORE. NOT EVERYONE CAN JOIN BUT YOU
KNOW WE HAVE A REALLY GREAT REPRESENTATION HERE OF THE
STAKEHOLDERS INTO ORGANIZATIONS THAT WE WORK WITH.
WE ARE SO HAPPY TO REACH THIS TEN YEAR MILESTONE ANNIVERSARY
ESPECIALLY TO SURVIVE THE PANDEMIC AND EVEN TO COME OUT
STRONGER THROUGH THE PANDEMIC ECONOMIC RECESSION AND ATTACKS
AGAINST IMMIGRANTS. AND DESPITE ONGOING THREATS OF
DISPLACEMENT AND DEFENDING OUR COMMUNITIES CONTINUE TO SHOW UP
FOR EACH OTHER AND WORK WITH OTHER IMMIGRANT COMMUNITIES
AND CULTURAL DISTRICTS TO FIGHT FOR THE RIGHT TO HAVE A FUTURE
IN THE CITY. >> SAMA PILIPINAS TEN YEAR
IMPACT COULD NOT HAVE BEEN POSSIBLE WITHOUT THE SUSTAINED
PARTNERSHIP OF LEGACY FILIPINO ARTS AND COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS WHOSE ROOTS IN THE SOUTH THE MARKET RUNS
DECADES DEEP. MUCH LONGER THAN THE TEN YEAR
ANNIVERSARY THAT WE'RE CELEBRATING TODAY.
WE ARE JOINED HERE BY COMMUNITY LEADERS WHO HAVE BEEN WORKING
THE CULTURAL DISTRICT FOR THE LAST TEN YEARS.
>> SOME FOR THE LAST. MANY HERE ACTUALLY FOR THE LAST
20 YEARS AND SOME FOR OVER 30 YEARS ALTHOUGH YOU COULDN'T
TELL BECAUSE THEY LOOK EVERY YOUNG CAME THROUGH THE.
>> LET ME SEE IF I CAN GO. >> FIRST AND FOREMOST WE WOULD
LIKE TO ACKNOWLEDGE AND THANK THE FILIPINO AMERICAN
DEVELOPMENT FOUNDATION, OUR MOTHER ORGANIZATION ADF.
WE HAVE M.S. BERNICE AND JOHNNY HERE AND I THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US. AND OUR SIBLING PROGRAMS
FILIPINO EDUCATION CENTER GALING BATA AND FILIPINO MENTAL
HEALTH INITIATIVE AND I THINK I SEE CHANCE HERE THE BOARD
PRESIDENT WILL PROBABLY ASK YOU TO DO THE WAVE THING SO CLAP
OUR COMMITTEE PARTNERS IN ANTI DISPLACEMENT AND HOUSING RIGHTS
SOME COUNTIES HERE THINK WE HAVE JERICHO AND RAMON THIS AT
THE MARKET COMMUNITY ACTION NETWORK HAVE PROTECTED SO MANY
FILIPINO FAMILIES FROM DISPLACEMENT AND WE'RE ALSO
JOINED BY BISHOP THE HOUSING PROGRAM WHICH HAS HELPED
HUNDREDS OF MIGRANT FAMILIES FIND PERMANENT AFFORDABLE
HOUSING IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD. AND WE'RE HERE WITH PLANNING
COMMISSIONER TERESA IMPERIALE WHO'S ONE OF THE FOUNDERS
AND THE NEW EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR RACONTEUR.
>> I ALSO WANT TO RECOGNIZE IRENE ALMARIO ARTISTIC DIRECTOR
OF BENTO STUDIO OVER SINCE THE 90S WINDOWS STAFF HAS DEVELOPED
HUNDREDS OF MAINSTAGE PRODUCTIONS AND ALSO AN EVEN
EVEN MORE COMMUNITY BASED ACTORS, PLAYWRIGHTS
AND PRODUCERS TO TELL THE FILIPINO AMERICAN STORY.
>> THIS WEEKEND THEY'RE PRESENTING COOL ARTS BURDEN OF
PROOF WHICH HAS RECEIVED A GREAT REVIEW FROM S.F.
CHRONICLE. SO WE HOPE WE GET OUT.
YOU CAN CHECK IT OUT. COOL ARTS HAS BEEN AROUND FOR
OVER 40 YEARS AND HAS BEEN REALLY MAKING CULTURE
AND SHIFTING CULTURE IN SOMA FOR DECADES.
>> I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE LUISA ANTONIO AND MARY ROQUE
FROM THE BAYANIHAN EQUITY CENTER BOTH WEARING MONKEY BACA
SWEATSHIRTS AND MARIA TERESA TEN MAN TERESA TEN FROM CANON
KIPP CENTER YOU WOULDN'T KNOW IT BUT THEY'VE BEEN SERVING THE
SOMA DISTRICT FOR DECADES EVERY DAY SERVING SENIORS, PROVIDING
THEM A WARM MEAL AND ALSO MAKING SURE THEY HAVE OUTLETS
FOR THEIR SINGING AND DANCING AND ALL OF THEIR TALENTS.
OUR LEGACY SMALL BUSINESSES ARE HERE STILL CELIA'S CLEANER
CELLULAR SELF IN PAUL AND OF COURSE AT THE AT ITS OF JT'S
RESTAURANT WHO'S BEEN HONORED HERE MANY TIMES BOTH BUSINESSES
HAVE BEEN SERVING THE NEIGHBORHOOD FOR CLOSE TO THREE
DECADES. WE ARE ALSO JOINED BY CAT
GENNARO WHO'S THE PRESIDENT OF APOLLO SAN FRANCISCO CHAPTER
AND MEMBERS OF THE FILIPINO COMMUNITY CENTER AND MALAY
MOVEMENT RACHEL AND GLENN WE PARTNER WITH ALL THREE
ORGANIZATIONS TO FIGHT FOR IMMIGRANT RIGHTS WORKERS RIGHTS
AND HUMAN RIGHTS. AND IT'S SO IMPORTANT AT THIS
TIME WHEN ALL OF THOSE RIGHTS ARE UNDER ATTACK.
>> WE ALSO HAVE JOSE PETRO OF THE FILIPINO CHAMBER OF
COMMERCE, PRESIDENT OF FILIPINO CHAMBER OF COMMERCE IS A BIG
SUPPORTER AND DESI DARDEN FROM CULTIVATE LABS WHO POPULARIZED
NIGHT MARKETS IN THE CITY. >> AND IT'S SO GREAT TO SEE NOW
NIGHT MARKETS HAPPENING IN ALMOST EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD
AND WE ALSO AND THEY ALSO SERVED ON OUR ADVISORY
COMMITTEE WANT TO SHE'S SITTING DOWN BUT OLIVIA ONGPIN WHO
HELPED PRODUCE OUR MAKI BACA EXHIBIT BRINGING OVER 4000
PEOPLE TO TABERNA FOR THE EXHIBIT LAST YEAR AND JAN TELL
LABYRINTH SO WHO IS OUR CHESS COORDINATOR?
>> SHE'S WITH REP AND HELPED WRITE THE 100 PAGE REPORT.
>> DID I FORGET? AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST I WOULD
LIKE TO PERSONALLY EXTEND MY DEEPEST GRATITUDE TO THE SUMMER
PILIPINAS TEAM THAT DIDN'T HAVE ALL OUR COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT
COORDINATOR CHRISTINE ABEBA OUR ARTS AND ADMINISTRATOR DAVID
WU, OUR LAND USE AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT COORDINATOR NEXT
GARY OUR MARKETING COORDINATOR WHO COULDN'T BE HERE AND MARIA
DE MIRA OUR ASSISTANT DIRECTOR LEADING PROGRAMS AND OPERATIONS
AND THE JEEPNEY DRIVER I COULDN'T WISH FOR A BETTER TEAM
TO DO THIS WORK WITH EVERY DAY .
>> I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE SOME OF OUR CHAMPIONS IN CITY
GOVERNMENT BESIDES ALL OF YOU. THERE'S TWO FOLKS IN THE
DEPARTMENT IMANI FROM CD APRIL FROM IWD.
>> I SAW JOCELYN MANALO EARLIER OTHER FOLKS IN THE BACK SO DID
I FORGET AND VERY I'M GOING TO BE IN TROUBLE IF I DID.
OKAY WELL JUST WANT TO SAY THANK YOU BY TO SUPERVISORS BUT
REALLY THINK EVERYONE HERE IT'S BEEN AN HONOR TO SERVE WITH ALL
OF YOU AND WE'RE LOOKING FORWARD TO THE NEXT TEN YEARS
OF SOME OF FILIPINOS. >> OKAY.
YES, THERE IT'S REALLY EASY, BABY.
>> I KNOW IN THE HALLWAY. YEAH, I GUESS I GO ALL RIGHT.
AND NEXT WE HAVE DISTRICT TEN SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, PRESIDENT MADAM AND COLLEAGUES.
TODAY I STAND TO HONOR THE CURTIS FAMILY SEE NOTES.
>> IT IS BOTH AN HONOR AND A JOY TO STAND BEFORE YOU TODAY
TO RECOGNIZE A FAMILY WHOSE IMPACT ON SAN FRANCISCO REACHES
FAR BEYOND THE STAGE, FAR BEYOND MUSIC AND DEEP INTO THE
HEART OF OUR COMMUNITY. MANY FIRST CAME TO KNOW THE
CURTIS FAMILY THROUGH THEIR UNFORGETTABLE APPEARANCE ON
AMERICA'S GOT TALENT. BUT HERE IN THE BAY AREA
AND ESPECIALLY IN BAY VIEW, WE KNOW THEM AS SOMETHING EVEN
MORE SPECIAL A LIVING BREATHING EXAMPLE OF WHAT IT MEANS TO USE
TALENT IN SERVICE OF COMMUNITY .
FRESH OFF A REMARKABLE TOUR ACROSS 18 STATES FROM
WASHINGTON, D.C. TO NEW ORLEANS ,THEY HAVE CARRIED THE SPIRIT
OF SAN FRANCISCO WITH THEM SHARING SONGS FROM THEIR LATEST
ALBUM AWAKENED THREE AND SPREADING A MESSAGE OF
UNITY, LOVE AND CULTURAL PRIDE WHEREVER THEY GO.
AND YET NO MATTER HOW FAR THEIR MUSIC TRAVELS, THEIR ROOTS
REMAIN FIRMLY PLANTED HERE AT HOME.
THE CURTIS FAMILY. PAPA SEE MAMA C AND THEIR
INCREDIBLE CHILDREN ZAHARA NOW ICES KIKI AND PHENIX ARE MORE
THAN PERFORMERS. THEY ARE EDUCATORS.
THEY ARE BRIDGE BUILDERS. THEY ARE HEALERS THROUGH THEIR
NONPROFIT PASSING THE TORCH. THEY HAVE CREATED POWERFUL
INTERGENERATIONAL SPACES WHERE SENIORS AND YOUNG PEOPLE COME
TOGETHER THROUGH MUSIC, STORYTELLING AND SHARED
EXPERIENCE. IN A TIME WHEN SO MANY FEEL
DISCONNECTED, THEY HAVE CHOSEN CONNECTION IN A TIME OF
ISOLATION. THEY HAVE CHOSEN COMMUNITY
DURING THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC WHEN FEAR AND UNCERTAINTY
GRIPPED OUR CITY. THE CURTIS FAMILY SHOWED US
WHAT COURAGE LOOKS LIKE. THEY STEPPED FORWARD NOT JUST
AS ARTISTS BUT AS NEIGHBORS DELIVERING GROCERIES, OFFERING
COMFORT AND LIFTING SPIRITS WITH SONGS THAT REMINDED PEOPLE
THEY WERE NOT ALONE. >> THEIR MUSICAL EXCELLENCE HAS
TAKEN THEM TO LEGENDARY STAGES LIKE YOSHI'S BLUE NOTE JAZZ
CLUB, FOX THEATER, CONCORD PAVILION AND THE BITTER END.
THEY HAVE SHARED THE STAGE WITH MUSICAL ICONS LIKE JOHN BAPTIST
AND LAYLA HATHAWAY. YET THEY CONTINUE TO PUSH FOR
THAT SAME LEVEL OF PASSION AND EXCELLENCE RIGHT BACK INTO
THEIR OWN COMMUNITY. >> THEIR COMMITMENT TO ACCESS
AND EDUCATION IS EQUALLY PROFOUND.
AS FACULTY AND STUDENTS AT THE SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY MUSIC
CENTER, THEY EMBODY THE BELIEF THAT MUSIC BELONGS TO EVERYONE
REGARDLESS OF AGE, BACKGROUND OR INCOME.
>> AND AS THEY STEP INTO AN EXCITING NEW CHAPTER DEVELOPING
A TELEVISION SITCOM THAT CELEBRATES THEIR LOVE STORY
WITH SAN FRANCISCO ALONGSIDE ACCLAIMED PRODUCERS LIKE JAMIE
FOX AND HIS CREATIVE PARTNERS THAT CONTINUE TO ELEVATE NOT
ONLY THEIR FAMILY'S STORY BUT THE STORY OF OUR CITY.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT CAUSED ME TO HAVE SUCH HIGH ADMIRATION
FOR THEM IS THE FACT THAT THEY KNOW NOT ONLY CAN JUST SING BUT
THEY ALL PLAY INSTRUMENTS AS WELL.
THEY ALSO KEEP UP WITH CURRENT AFFAIRS.
AND I REMEMBER MEETING WITH THEM AND EVERY LAST ONE OF THEM
HAD A SERIOUS QUESTION ABOUT HOW I WAS GOING TO WORK TO
IMPROVE THE DISTRICT. I AM SO PROUD THEY ARE FROM MY
COMMUNITY AND RESIDENTS OF DISTRICT TEN.
TODAY WE HONOR THE CURTIS FAMILY NOT JUST FOR THEIR
EXTRAORDINARY MUSICAL GIFTS BUT FOR THEIR UNWAVERING COMMITMENT
TO JUSTICE EQUITY, COMMUNITY AND CARE.
THEY REMIND US THAT ART IS NOT SEPARATE FROM SERVICE.
IT IS ONE OF THE MOST POWERFUL FORMS OF IT.
IT IS MY GREAT PRIVILEGE TO COMMEND THE CURTIS FAMILY FOR
THEIR OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTIONS THEIR INSPIRING LEADERSHIP
AND THEIR CONTINUED DEDICATION TO UPLIFTING EVERY CORNER OF
OUR COMMUNITY. >> AND SUPERVISOR MAHMUD HAVE
SOME WORDS AS WELL. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WALTON
FOR AMAZING COMMENDATION. >> I HAVE PERSONALLY SEEN THE
CURTIS FAMILY IN SO MANY DIFFERENT WALKS OF LIFE IN THE
FILLMORE. I THINK WE FIRST MET ON A SMALL
BUSINESS MERCHANT WALK AND ACTUALLY EVEN BEFORE THAT I
MET YOU AT YOUR CHURCH BY SURPRISE.
>> JONES JUST YEAH HESWALL. BUT THE VERY FIRST TIME I SAW
YOU WAS WHEN YOU PERFORMED AT AND SPOKE AT REVEREND
TOWNSEND'S FUNERAL ACTUALLY. AND SO I'VE SEEN HOW YOU'VE
PERSONALLY TOUCHED EVERY WALK OF LIFE IN THE FILLMORE FROM
COMMUNITIES OF FAITH TO WHEN OUR COMMUNITY NEEDS UPLIFTING
THE MOST. WHEN SOMEONE HAS PASSED AWAY TO
REVITALIZING OUR ECONOMY WITH OUR SMALL BUSINESS CORRIDOR
IN THE FILLMORE. AND YOU DO IT ALL AS A FAMILY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU GUYS STICK TOGETHER.
FAMILIES ARE COMPLICATED BUT SOMEHOW YOU'RE ABLE TO PERFORM
AND WE SEE THE JOY AND THE UNITY AND THEN YOU INSPIRE US
TO BE BETTER THROUGH YOUR FAMILY, THROUGH YOUR HOPE
AND THROUGH YOUR LOVE. >> AND SO THANK YOU FOR
BRINGING THAT INSPIRATION TO SAN FRANCISCO.
THANK YOU TO THE SUPERVISORS. THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THIS IS SUCH AN AUSPICIOUS OCCASION FOR US TO BE
RECOGNIZED IN THIS WAY FOR THE WORK THAT WE HAVE DONE IN OUR
COMMUNITY. WE ARE COMMUNITY ACTIVISTS.
SOMETIMES WE DO IT THROUGH OUR MUSIC.
SOMETIMES WE DO IT WALKING THE STREETS.
AND SO IT HAS BEEN AN HONOR TO BE A PART OF THIS.
WE SHARE THIS HONOR WITH THE GODPARENTS AND THE UNCLES WHO
HAVE BEEN AND AUNTIES WHO HAVE MADE SURE THAT THE MUSIC WAS
ALWAYS ON POINT FIRST OF ALL. BUT THE OTHER THING IS THAT WE
ARE SURROUNDED BY A LOT OF PEOPLE WITH LOVE.
>> MISS MISS LINETTE MACKEY PEOPLE LIKE FELICIA THIBODEAUX
WHO RUNS A PROGRAM AT BOOKMAN MOTHER BROWN'S KITCHEN.
THESE ARE AVENUES THAT WE HAVE TAKEN TO GO INTO AND HELP THEM
TO HELP THE COMMUNITY. AND IT IS AN HONOR FOR US AND I
SPEAK FOR MY WIFE AS YOU HONOR US.
WE WANT TO HONOR YOU WITH ONE OF THE GREATEST SONGS EVER MADE
WRITTEN ABOUT A CITY. THE MOST BEAUTIFUL SONG IN FACT
IT'S EVER BEEN DONE. ONE LOVE.
LOVE IS LOVE. >> ALVIN'S SINGING SOMEHOW
SADLY GAY LOVE BEAUTY THAT WAS OH SEVEN THE DAY HE I'VE BEEN
TOTALLY ALONE AND FORGOTTEN AND THEN HOME.
I'M GOING HOME TO MY DIVINE LOVE.
BUT WHEN MAY I REST MY LOVE IT MADE SAN FRANCISCO HOME.
UP ON THE HILL IT'S CLOSE TO ME TO BE WHERE LITTLE TABLES GONE
. >> I'M HALFWAY TO THE STAR
IN THE MORNING FOG MAY CHILL THE AIR.
>> I DON'T CARE MY LOVE WAS THERE IN SAN FRANCISCO OH ABOVE
THE BLUE OH AND CITY WHOA. I GO HOME TO SAN FRANCISCO OH
YOUR GOLDEN SUN SHONE. >> OH, WE REALLY
MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENTS.
AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT.
PLEASE LINE UP TO SPEAK ON THE RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER
ALONG THE CURTAINS. YOU MAY SPEAK TO THE MINUTES AS
PRESENTED ITEMS 34 THROUGH 40 WHICH ARE MATTERS ON THE FLOOR
ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA AND GENERAL
MATTERS NOT ON THE PUBLISHED AGENDA BUT WITHIN THE BOARD
SUBJECT MATTER JURISDICTION. ALL OTHER AGENDA CONTENT WILL
HAVE BEEN REPORTED OUT TO THE BOARD BY AN APPROPRIATE
COMMITTEE WHERE THE PUBLIC COMMENT REQUIREMENT OCCURRED.
FIRST SPEAKER YES GUY OF THIS PROJECTOR PLEASE.
>> S.F. GOV TV THANK YOU. MY NAME IS JERRY DE RATTLER.
IN SEPTEMBER OF 2025 THE BOARD APPROVED THE PURCHASE OF 1660
MISSION STREET, THE FORMER HOME OF THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT
AND THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING INSPECTION FOR $18.5 MILLION.
THE BUILDING WAS COMPLETED ON A $5 MILLION BUILDING PERMIT
IN 1999 THAT EXPIRED IN 1992 AND EXPIRED BUILDING PERMIT IS
NULL AND VOID. >> THERE ARE NO DEBRIS FIELD
INSPECTIONS ON THE BUILDING PERMIT AND NONE OF THE PERMIT
SPECIAL INSPECTIONS WERE APPROVED BY DVI.
I FORWARDED EACH OF YOU A COPY OF AN EMAIL I SENT TO THE
DIRECTORS OF DBI AND PLANNING REQUESTING THE $5 MILLION
BUILDING PERMIT BE REVOKED AND A NOTICE OF VIOLATION
ISSUED. I ALSO REQUESTED THAT NEW
BUILDING PERMITS FOR THE $57 MILLION OF PLANNED RENOVATIONS
WOULD NOT BE APPROVED UNTIL AN INDEPENDENT LICENSED
PROFESSIONAL DETERMINES THE BUILDING IS CODE COMPLIANT.
IN 2020 DUBAI FINALIZED THE NULL AND VOID BUILDING PERMIT.
FORMER BUILDING INSPECTOR BERNIE CURRAN APPROVED AN
ADMINISTRATIVE PERMIT TO FINAL THE EXPIRED PERMIT AND MATTHEW
GREEN, THE CURRENT DEPUTY DIRECTOR OF DUBAI FINAL THE
PERMIT HONORED CERTIFICATE OF FINAL COMPLETION BETWEEN 1993
AND 2020 1660 MISSION STREET DID NOT HAVE A CERTIFICATE OF
OCCUPANCY AND DVI IN THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT ILLEGALLY
OCCUPIED THE SPACE. THE GEO SUBCOMMITTEE OF THE
BOARD NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THE CITY'S INVOLVEMENT WITH THIS
PROPERTY. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER HELLO SUPERVISORS.
>> I'M HERE TO TALK ABOUT WHAT WE NEED FROM YOU GUYS.
>> WE NEED TO TO USE YOUR YOUR POWER TO INVESTIGATE THE
MANAGEMENT AND OWNERSHIP OF THOMAS PAINE SQUARE APARTMENTS
. FOR YEARS RESIDENTS HAVE HAD
THEIR CHECKS GO MISSING, THEIR MONEY ORDERS GO MISSING.
DON'T MISS THE MANAGEMENT COMPANY MAKES RESIDENTS PAY
RENT WITH CASHIER'S CHECKS THEN NEVER GET CREDITED TO THEIR
ACCOUNT. ALSO WITH THE MONEY YOU ORDERS
THEY DO THAT THE SAME BECAUSE THEY'VE DONE THAT TO ME A FEW
TIMES. >> I WAS JUST LUCKY TO HAVE A
LAWYER. SOME PEOPLE AREN'T LUCKY LIKE
THAT. THOMAS PAINE WHERE WE JUST HAD
A ROBBERY AND THEY JUST MOVED THE CRIMINALS ONE IS THAT A
SISTER PLACE AND THE OTHER ONES THEY LET GO.
THEY WON'T HAND OVER RECORDS THAT ARE LEGALLY SUPPOSED TO BE
HANDED OVER FROM THE FEDERAL LAW.
THE PRIVACY ACT OF 1970 BOARD REQUIRES FOR THOMAS PAINE TO
SHARE OUR LEDGERS. >> OUR LEDGERS, PLEASE HELP US
OUT. THIS IS GOING ON.
>> THEY STOLEN THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS FROM THE TENETS.
>> THEY WON'T DO WHAT THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO DO.
WE'VE SEEN SO MANY CHANGES AND IT'S NOT.
BUT THE GOOD IS FOR THE THE BAD.
>> WE'RE ASKING YOU WE'RE PLEADING WITH YOU.
>> PLEASE, PLEASE AND THAT'S THE GATE.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON.
YOUR. I'M FROM THOMAS PAINE SQUARE
ALSO A RESIDENCE OVER 50 SOME YEARS BUT AT THOMAS PAINE
SQUARE. >> I HAVE SEEN SO MANY MANAGERS
SO MANY PEOPLE COME IN LIKE SHE SAID, WE HAD A RESIDENT THAT
GOT ROBBED. THEY DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
THEY LET THEM WALK. THEY FIRED HIM BUT THEY GET TO
COME ON THE PREMISES. THEY STAY AROUND THE CORNER.
THEY BE EVERYWHERE BUT THEY NEVER TAKE CARE OF WHAT THEY
SUPPOSED TO BE. THOMAS PAINE HAD NEVER AS LONG
AS I'VE BEEN LIVING HERE THESE LAST 4 OR 5 YEARS I HAVE NOT
SEEN THOMAS PAINE EVADE AND STAY SELF UP.
ALL I EVER SEE IS THAT ALL THE BLACK FOLKS RED GO UP.
THEY RIDDEN OUT PRICES. THEY THEY LISTEN PLACES THEY
GET TO PLACES THE LEAST AMOUNT I'M NOT PREJUDICED BUT IS JUST
IDEA WHY WE CAN'T GET WHAT WE SUPPOSED TO GET AT THOMAS PAINE
SQUARE THEY HAVE STAINLESS STEEL REFRIGERATORS WHEN I HAVE
A WHITE ONE I TOOK ME FOUR MONTHS TO GET MY REFRIGERATOR
TO GET A NEW ONE THAT WAS LEAKING.
THEY CAME IN LOOK IT UP. OH, WE'RE GOING TO TRY THIS.
THEY TRIED IT. IT DID WORK.
FINALLY THEY BOUGHT ME A REFRIGERATOR AND THEN THEY SAY
WE ONLY HAVE A BUDGET OF $200 IF YOU ONLY GOT A BUDGET OF
$200. WE GOT PEOPLE STAYING AT THOMAS
PAINE SQUARE. THAT CARPET HAS BEEN IN THE
SAME PLACES FOR 30 SOME YEARS. THEY HAVE NOT MOVED THAT
CARPET. THEY TALK ABOUT COMING OUT
MEASURE WHY DO YOU HAVE TO MEASURE THE CARPET THAT THE
SAME THING IN THE SAME PLACE IF YOU GOT A THREE BEDROOM YOU
ALREADY MEASURES ALL THE THREE BEDROOMS APARTMENT YOU MEASURE
THE TWO YOU MEASURE THE POINT IN A ONE BEDROOM THEY ARE THE
SAME MEASUREMENTS GET THE CARPET DONE, THEY REMOVE THE
PADDING EVEN PUT NEW PADDING UP UNDERNEATH THINGS.
THOMAS PAINE HAS BEEN SO BAD, SAYS DOMAS HAS BEEN THE COMPANY
THAT WE HAVE TO BE. I HAVE NOTHING ELSE SAY JUST
GET US TO HAVE SOME HELP PLEASE.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER HELLO. GOOD AFTERNOON.
ALSO LIVE IN THOMAS PAINE SQUARE APARTMENTS IN FILLMORE,
SAN FRANCISCO. MY NAME IS JESSICA SALINAS
AND I'M A RESIDENT OF THOMAS PAINE SQUARE APARTMENTS.
FOR THE PAST FOUR YEARS I HAVE BEEN A VICTIM OF CRIME
AND HARASSMENT AT THOMAS PAINE SQUARE APARTMENTS.
I'VE HAD MY TIRES SLASHED, STOPPED MY CHILDREN THREATENED
BY THE SAME RESIDENT. I'VE REACHED OUT TO OWNERSHIP
AND TO OUR MANAGER DOMAS. BUT NOTHING HAS BEEN DONE.
OUR SECURITY IS WORTHLESS AND IS OWNED BY BOBBY SISK WHO
IS A CHAIR OF THE BOARD THAT CONTROLS THOMAS PAINE SQUARE
APARTMENTS AND IS A STEWARD OF BETHEL A.M.E..
UNDER LAW HE SHOULD NOT BE ABLE TO CONTRACT OUT TO A COMPANY HE
OWNS BUT THAT DOESN'T STOP HIM. WE PAID 3600 PER UNIT FOR
SECURITY EVERY YEAR WHICH IS WAY MORE THAN OUR BUILDINGS.
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN SECURITY WALK THE PROPERTY.
THE SAN FRANCISCO STUDENT STANDARD RECENTLY DID A STORY
ON THAT AND REVEALED THAT BOBBY WAS OVERPAID MILLIONS OF
DOLLARS BY THE SAN FRANCISCO HOUSING AUTHORITY.
THE CITY COULD HAVE INVESTIGATED BOBBY SIX YEARS
AGO BUT THEY DIDN'T. WHICH HAS ALLOWED HIM TO MAKE
MORE MONEY OFF OF OUR MISERY. I FACE DEATH.
I FACED DEATH THREATS DUE TO THE TERRIBLE SECURITY AT THOMAS
PAINE SQUARE APARTMENTS. AND WE'VE HAD OTHER RESIDENTS
WHO HAVE BEEN NEARLY KILLED IN ATTACKS.
THE SAME MAN WHO HAS THREATENED ME WAS IN AN INSTIGATOR OF SOME
OF THE RECENT ATTACKS ON OTHER WOMEN AT THOMAS PAINE SQUARE
APARTMENTS. WE NEED THE CITY ATTORNEY TO
INVESTIGATE MY BOYS. SISK AND MAKE SURE HE CAN
RECEIVE NO MORE MONEY FROM THE CITY.
WE NEED A NEW SECURITY COMPANY A THOMAS PAINE SQUARE
APARTMENTS THAT HAS NO CONNECTIONS TO BOBBY SISK HIS
GREED HAS ENDANGERED US AND WE NEED THE CITY TO STOP THAT.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER A MY NAME IS PAT COCHRAN.
I'M AN ORGANIZER WITH THE RESIDENTS AT THOMAS PAINE
SQUARE AND I'M OBVIOUSLY HERE TODAY TO SPEAK ABOUT THE LIVING
CONDITIONS THERE AND EVERYTHING THAT GOES ON.
IF YOU LOOK UP THOMAS PAINE SQUARE IN YOUR PHONE YOU WILL
SEE A SERIES OF ARTICLES OVER THE LAST YEAR.
YOU'LL SEE STAFF MEMBERS THAT WERE CAUGHT STEALING CHRISTMAS
GIFTS. YOU'LL SEE THAT BOBBY SMITH,
THE GUY WHO CONTROLS THE BOARD HAS MADE IS OVERCHARGES BY
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS FOR SECURITY THAT IS
INADEQUATE AND HAS LED THE PEOPLE GETTING ATTACKED DEATH
THREATS AND BASICALLY THIS IS A PROBLEM ESPECIALLY WITH BOBBY
SAYS THE CITY COULD HAVE TAKEN CARE OF THIS DECADES AGO.
IF YOU LOOK UP THE S.F. STANDARD STORY, HE WAS OVERPAID
BY THE HOUSING AUTHORITY MILLIONS OF DOLLARS THAT SHOULD
HAVE THEY SHOULD HAVE STOPPED HIM FROM GETTING ANY CONTRACTS
AND BECAUSE THE CITY HAS NOT BEEN UP TO ON TAKING CARE OF
THIS ISSUE, THIS HAS JUST GONE DOWNHILL AND HAS GOTTEN WORSE
AND WORSE AND WORSE. THERE'S BEEN PEOPLE HAVE DIED
IN FIRES. THERE'S THE MOLD, ASBESTOS JUST
EVERYTHING TERRIBLE YOU CAN THINK OF AND WE ALL KNOW
IN THIS CITY ABOUT YOU KNOW, THE FILLMORE REDEVELOPED IN THE
50S THEY ARE DOING THE EXACT SAME THING RIGHT NOW.
THEY ARE TAKING THEY'RE EVICTING BLACK RESIDENTS, MANY
OF THEM WHO'VE HAD THEIR CASHIER'S CHECK STOLEN
AND THERE'S AND IT DOESN'T SEEM LIKE THERE'S MUCH HELP.
I GOT TO THANK THE FLOOD SUPERVISOR FOR, YOU KNOW,
REACHING OUT TO THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE.
BUT OBVIOUSLY WE NEED MORE HELP THAN THIS.
THIS IS A SERIOUS LIVING CONDITION AND TRUST ME, IF THIS
ISN'T TAKEN CARE OF, PEOPLE WILL DIE.
TRUST ME ON THIS. IT IS BAD.
IT IS EVERYTHING BAD YOU CAN THINK ABOUT A HOUSE HOUSING YOU
KNOW THE BUILDING THOMAS PAINE HAS AND WE NEED THE CITY TO
STEP UP TO MAKE SURE THAT WE CAN STOP THIS AND PROTECT THESE
RESIDENTS. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER YES, GOOD
AFTERNOON. I GET THE OVERHEAD PROJECTOR AS
A BACKUP TO BE THANK YOU. >> MY NAME IS ERIC SEDGLEY
AND I JUST WANTED THREE MINUTES NOT A LONG TIME BUT I WANT TO
THANK SUPER FOR MELGAR FOR REVEREND G.
I'M A FORMER RESIDENT 72 LOBO STREET ATTENDED REVEREND G'S
CHURCH AND VISITED MAYFLOWER RESTAURANT MANY YEARS, JUST
WENT TO HIS CHURCH LAST SUNDAY AND THE FORMER SUNDAY BEFORE HE
PASSED. I'M NOW A RESIDENT OF THE
FILLMORE FOR OVER 50 YEARS AND AS A RESIDENT JUST SPOKE
ABOUT THOMAS PAINE. >> OUR WHOLE FAMILY NEEDS HELP,
RIGHT? I CAME HERE TO ASK FOR HELP
BEFORE EVEN WITH LARGE COMMUNITY CENTER NOT YOU KNOW,
THE DETERIORATION OF THE BUILDING AND AS REVEREND G'S
PICTURE IS ALL PART OF THE BUILDING THAT'S CRACKING IN THE
FOUNDATION, WE REALLY NEED HELP, RIGHT?
WE'VE BEEN NEEDING HELP FOR YEARS AND UNFORTUNATELY, YOU
KNOW, WE'RE NOT GETTING THE HELP THAT WE NEED.
RIGHT? THE FILLMORE SAFEWAY CLOSED
AND NOW I'M ORGANIZING IT BECAUSE GROCERY STORES ARE AN
ISSUE IN SAN FRANCISCO RIGHT NOW.
RIGHT. YOU TALKED ABOUT HEARING FOR
DOGS AND YOU KNOW WE NEED A HEARING FOR GROCERY STORES,
RIGHT? WE NEED TO GET UNDERSTAND WHAT
ARE WE DOING WITH ALL THESE GROCERY STORES AND EVERY
NEIGHBORHOOD THERE'S A GROCERY STORE ALMOST CLOSING IN SAN
FRANCISCO RIGHT. AND ONE OF OUR PRIME
DEVELOPMENTS IS THE SAFEWAY STORE IN FILLMORE THAT WE'RE
NOT GETTING NO JUSTICE WITH AND THEY'RE LEADING THE CASE
WITH THIS DEVELOPMENT COMPANY THAT'S GOING TO REDO ALL
SAFEWAY STORES. SO WE REALLY NEED HELP.
SO I'M CALLING FOR A HEARING A TOWN HALL MEETING NEXT THURSDAY
AT THE SAN FRANCISCO LIBRARY JUST TO START THE PROCESS.
SO MAX AND ONE OF YOUR COLLEAGUES YOU'LL ASSIST IS
SOMEBODY TO COME OUT AND HELP WITH THIS PROCESS.
YOU KNOW, AND THIS IS THE BEGINNING, RIGHT?
I'M GOING ACROSS THE CITY NOW TO ORGANIZE AND HELP MY
COMMUNITY BECAUSE THE FILLMORE NEEDS HELP BEEN NEEDING HELP
AND WE'RE NOT GETTING THE JUSTICE WE NEED.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON YOU ARE MY NAME IS JALEN TILLIS
AND I'M 26 YEARS OLD. LONG STORY SHORT THERE ARE FOUR
PROBLEMS THAT I HAVE THAT I WOULD LIKE TO DISCUSS TO THIS
MATTER. ONE THERE IS A LOT OF
DEFECATION AND THERE IS A LOT OF URINATION ON THE STREETS OF
SAN FRANCISCO AND I FEEL LIKE NOT ONLY IT IS BAD TO THE
ENVIRONMENT BUT IT'S ALSO BAD TO THE YOUTH THAT HAVE TO WALK
THESE STREETS. AND PERSONALLY I FEEL LIKE WE
NEED MORE BATHROOMS IN THE PUBLIC SO PEOPLE WOULDN'T HAVE
TO URINATE AND DEFECATE. THEY SHOULDN'T HAVE TO BE TO
WHERE EVERYWHERE I WALK I HAVE TO LOOK DOWN THE MAKES RIGHT
OUT STEP AND FECES. I ALSO FEEL LIKE IT'S MESSING
UP THE OZONE LAYER AND I ALSO FEEL LIKE IT'S MESSING UP THE
AIR QUALITY AS WELL. >> AND THE LAST LIKE THE SECOND
ONE GROCERY STORES, GROCERY STORES WE HAVE A PROBLEM WITH
DEATH IN THE CITY TOO. PERSONALLY I RECOMMEND HIRING
MORE SECURITY AND I RECOMMEND THAT INSTEAD OF TAKING IT OUT
ON THE CITIZENS WHO DO NOT STEAL IN SAN FRANCISCO WE HAVE
MORE STRICTER LAWS FOR PEOPLE WHO DO STILL SAME THING OR
PEOPLE WHO DEFECATE AND URINATE IN THE STREETS.
>> AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST, WE STILL HAVE A MAJOR DRUG PROBLEM
HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO A BUNCH OF PEOPLE SMOKING 30 IN FRONT
OF DAYCARES AND SCHOOLS, A BUNCH OF PEOPLE LIKE DOING OPEN
AIR DRUG DEALING LIKE AT NIGHT YOU KNOW, IN THE DAYTIME DANIEL
LURIE'S DOING A GOOD JOB BUT THERE'S A PART THAT HE'S NOT
COVERING WHICH IS AT NIGHT WHICH SAN FRANCISCO DATOS
IN PARTICULAR IS A TOTALLY DIFFERENT AREA AND THAT'S WHERE
YOU KNOW THE FREAKS COME OUT. AND PERSONALLY I THINK THAT IF
JAN LIKE FOR EXAMPLE DIDN'T WORK NINE SEARCHES LIKE RAN
CANINES FOR THE CITY IS A LOT MORE LIKE JUST RANDOMLY I FEEL
LIKE WE COULD CRACK DOWN ON MORE DRUG USAGE AS WELL AS DRUG
DEALING. AND ALSO I FEEL LIKE IF WE HAD
STRICTER PRECAUTIONS, A STRICTER PUNISHMENT.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
APOLOGIES FOR CUTTING YOU OFF OR PROVIDING EVERYONE THE SAME
TWO MINUTES. >> NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON
MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. MY NAME IS RYAN ORTIZ AND I
WORK AS A LEGISLATIVE INTERN AND SUPERVISOR DORSEY'S OFFICE.
I'M HERE TODAY TO SPEAK ON BEHALF OF ITEM NUMBER 34 WHICH
DECLARES APRIL 24TH 2026 AS ARBOR DAY.
OUR DAY IS A GLOBALLY RECOGNIZED CELEBRATION THAT
ENCOURAGES THE PLANTING, NURTURING AND CARE OF TREES
TREES PROVIDE US WITH MORE SHADE, BETTER AIR QUALITY NOISE
REDUCTION AND A SENSE OF CALM THAT WE COULD ALL USE IN THESE
TROUBLING TIMES. >> SHE'S GOING TO HAVE THE
GREATEST IMPACT ON QUALITY OF LIFE IN OUR MOST DENSE
NEIGHBORHOODS WHERE THERE ARE HIGH LEVELS OF POLLUTION, URBAN
HEAT AND LIMITED ACCESS TO GREEN INFRASTRUCTURE.
THIS TIME SERVES AS A TIME TO RECOGNIZE THE BEAUTY OF THE
NATURE THAT WE HAVE HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AS WELL AS A SENSE OF
COMMUNITY THAT IS CREATED AS A DIRECT RESULT OF THE EFFORTS
FROM OUR LOCAL ORGANIZATIONS. >> SO LET US TAKE THIS TIME
AND SPEND TO TAKE A WALK AND SPEND A LITTLE EXTRA TIME
APPRECIATING OUR TREES. JOIN THE CONVERSATION AS I
SUPPORT TREE PLANTING AND APPRECIATE THE EFFORTS OF
THOSE WHO MAKE A BETTER TOMORROW FOR US.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS DENISE HEIGHTS AND RYDER.
I'M THE MANAGER FOR STRATEGIC INITIATIVES AT THE DEPARTMENT
ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN. AND ON BEHALF OF THE
DEPARTMENT, I'M HERE TO SAY THANK YOU AND EXPRESS OUR
APPRECIATION AND SUPPORT FOR ITEM 38.
THE RESOLUTION IN SUPPORT OF APRIL BEING RECOGNIZED AS
SEXUAL ASSAULT AWARENESS MONTH. AS YOU ARE ALL AWARE, WE NOW
HAVE A WOMEN'S AGENDA FOR SAN FRANCISCO AND SOME OF THOSE KEY
PILLARS AND PARTS OF THAT AGENDA INVOLVE ENSURING THAT
WOMEN ARE SAFE HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND IN ALL PLACES
COMMUNITY SPACES, SCHOOLS, TRANSIT AS WELL AS IN THEIR
HOMES. WE KNOW THAT THERE ARE SPECIFIC
POPULATIONS IN THE CITY AND COUNTY INCLUDING TRANS
WOMEN WOMEN EXPERIENCING POVERTY AND HOUSING INSECURE
WOMEN ARE AT GREATER RISK OF SEXUAL ASSAULT.
AND WE WANT TO ENCOURAGE AND REQUEST THAT WE CONTINUE TO
MAKE SURE THAT THESE THE AGENCIES THAT PROVIDE CRUCIAL
FRONTLINE SUPPORT FOR INDIVIDUALS THAT HAVE
EXPERIENCED CRISIS CONTINUE TO RECEIVE FINANCIAL SUPPORT
AND YOUR SUPPORT IN THE COMING MONTHS.
WE NEED TO ENSURE THAT WE ARE CENTERING SURVIVOR SURVIVORS,
PROVIDING HOLISTIC WRAPAROUND SERVICES FOR THEM AND MAKING
SURE THAT WE ARE CENTERING PROVIDING CULTURALLY RELEVANT
SUPPORT TO THOSE THAT HAVE BEEN IMPACTED BY SEXUAL ASSAULT
AND VIOLENCE. WE ALSO NEED TO BEGIN TO
ADDRESS THE GROWING PROBLEM OF ONLINE HARASSMENT AND VIOLENCE
THAT HAS BEEN TRANSLATING TO MORE AND MORE REAL REAL WORLD
VIOLENCE. WE KNOW THAT A.I. HAS LED TO A
MASSIVE PROLIFERATION OF DEEPFAKES.
WE'VE SEEN TERRIBLE COVERAGE PARTICULARLY FROM CNN RECENTLY
ABOUT ONLINE RAPE ACADEMIES. AND WE KNOW THAT THIS IS AN
EMERGING PROBLEM FOR YOUNG WOMEN AND WOMEN OF ALL GENDERS
,TRANS INDIVIDUALS AND FOLKS ALL ACROSS THE SPECTRUM.
THANK YOU ALL FOR YOUR SUPPORT. THIS IS WORK THAT IS DONE
IN COMMUNITY WITH COMMUNITY AND WITH OUR CITY LEADERS.
AND WE'RE VERY GRATEFUL TO YOU FOR INTRODUCING THE RESOLUTION
AND SUPPORTING IT. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS JOSEPH AND I SERVE
AS THE ACTING DIRECTOR FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO YOUTH COMMISSION.
>> WE WANT TO FIRST THANK SUPERVISOR CHERYL MELGAR
AND CHEN FOR LEADING THIS RESOLUTION FOR NATIONAL SEXUAL
ASSAULT AWARENESS AND PREVENTION MONTH.
THIS RESOLUTION WAS ALSO INTRODUCED AT THE YOUTH
COMMISSION BY THE TWO COMMISSIONER CAMERON MALO
AND ALSO CITYWIDE COMMISSIONER JACQUELINE MORENO.
SO THIS IS AN ISSUE THAT THE COMMISSION HAPPENED
AND ADDRESSING AMONGST YOUNG PEOPLE FOR ABOUT 20 PLUS YEARS
NOW SINCE 2005 AND IT IS STILL A PREVAILING ISSUE AMONGST
YOUNG PEOPLE. >> SO IT'S NOT ENOUGH TO JUST
RECOGNIZE THIS MONTH EVERY MONTH THIS NEEDS TO BE
RECOGNIZED AND ALSO HOLD THE YOUTH COMMISSION IN OUR BUDGET
AND POLICY PRIORITIES. THIS YEAR IS ADVOCATING TO
ADDRESS AND MAKE SURE THAT WE ARE FUNDING ING EDUCATION
PROGRAMS AND AGENCIES AND COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS
THAT PROVIDE EDUCATION TO YOUNG PEOPLE TO RECOGNIZE SEXUAL
ASSAULT AND HARASSMENT AND TO PREVENT SEXUAL ASSAULT
AND HARASSMENT. SO WE THANK YOU FOR INTRODUCING
THIS RESOLUTION. WE DO ASK FOR UNANIMOUS SUPPORT
ON THIS AND TO MAKE SURE THAT YOUR BUDGET COMING IN JUNE ALSO
REFLECTS THIS. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> NEXT SPEAKER, I JUST WANTED
TO MAKE SURE I CAN WORK THIS DISPLAY.
YES, AS I'VE GOT TO BE. >> THANK YOU.
I'M PETER WARFIELD, EXECUTIVE. CAN I START THE TWO MINUTES
PLEASE? >> YOUR TWO MINUTES ARE
STARTED. >> I'M NOT GOING TO GET TWO
MINUTES. ALL RIGHT.
I'M DOWN TO 133 AND PETER WARFIELD, EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF
LIBRARY USERS ASSOCIATION. LIBRARY USERS 2004@YAHOO.COM
EXCUSE ME AT PROTON MAIL.COM AND P.O. BOX 170544 SAN
FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA 94117-0544 IT'S NATIONAL LIBRARY WEEK.
AND PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT AND I'M CERTAINLY GLAD TO JOIN
IN WITH TALKING ABOUT THE VALUE AND THE IMPORTANCE OF LIBRARIES
TO OUR CIVIC LIFE VALUE ESPECIALLY PUBLIC LIBRARIES TO
EVERY INDIVIDUAL, EVERY COMMUNITY IN OUR COUNTRY
AND BEYOND. THERE ARE GREAT ASSET
AND HELPING PEOPLE ENJOY AND APPRECIATE AND LEARN ABOUT
THE WORLD AROUND THEM AND WITHIN.
LAST MONTH THE SUN THE SUNSHINE ORDINANCE TASK FORCE FOUND THAT
THE LIBRARY COMMISSION WAS IN VIOLATION OF OPEN GOVERNMENT
LAW BY CUTTING ALL PUBLIC COMMENT FROM UP TO THREE
MINUTES TO TWO WITHOUT ANY KIND OF PROCESS OR EXPLANATION.
AND THAT WAS NOT THE ONLY THING THAT THEY DID LAST YEAR
STARTING EARLY LAST YEAR THEY CUT PUBLIC COMMENT ON A
PARTICULAR AGENDA ITEM WHICH THEY'D ALWAYS HAD PUBLIC
COMMENT ON AND A NUMBER OF OTHER ISSUES.
ONE OF THE THINGS I'M CONCERNED ABOUT IS THE LIBRARY'S CONSTANT
UNCRITICAL TOUTING OF SOCIAL MEDIA DESPITE THE FACT THAT
WE'VE WARNED THEM ABOUT THE DANGERS.
HERE'S AN EXAMPLE FROM AT THE LIBRARY AND HERE IS YOUTUBE.
>> HERE'S A HEADLINE FROM METTA FROM THE WALL STREET JOURNAL
ABOUT THE SERIOUS PROBLEMS THAT WERE DETERMINED IN A COURT CASE
WHICH AWARDED. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
. NEXT SPEAKER MY NAME IS RICHARD
STEVE PETERSON AND TODAY I'M ANNOUNCING THAT I'M GOING TO
RUN FOR SUPERVISOR OF DISTRICT EIGHT.
>> WELL NOT REALLY. >> IT'S A PRANK, MR. PETERSON
PASSING YOUR TIME. THERE'S NO THERE'S NO
ELECTIONEERING IN THIS CHAMBER. THANK YOU.
I'LL GO AHEAD AND RESTART. >> CONTINUE YOUR TIME.
OBVIOUSLY YOU DIDN'T HEAR MY ENTIRE REMARK.
YOU'VE BEEN FRANK BUT I WOULD LIKE TO GET TO SOME ISSUES THAT
I ENCOUNTERED UP. LIKE AS YOU KNOW, I'VE CHANGED
MY POSITION ON PARTIAL TAXES AND I'M A GREAT SUPPORTER OF
THE MUNI YET ALL OF A SUDDEN I RECEIVED IN THE MAIL FROM AN
INCIDENT THAT I THOUGHT I WAS GETTING A WARNING WHEN I WAS
INTERFERING WITH APPARENTLY TWO TRANSIT OFFICERS THAT WERE
AGGRESSIVELY QUESTIONING A. AN ASIAN PERSON WHO COULDN'T
SPEAK ENGLISH AND OF COURSE MY MOUTH GET ME IN TROUBLE AND SO
THEY GAVE ME WHAT I THOUGHT WAS A WARNING.
BUT APPARENTLY IT'S A WHOLE NEW $34 FINE THAT YOU GET WHEN YOU
WHEN YOU APPARENTLY DON'T DISPLAY.
AND IF ANYBODY CAN TELL ME WHAT THE WHAT THE OFFENSE IS FOR NOT
DISPLAYING. >> I HAD MY IDENTITY I HAD MY
MY TRANSIT CARD BUT I, I DIDN'T GIVE HIM THE TRANSIT CARD TO
SHOW THAT IT'S BEEN USING USE BUT THAT IS VERY DANGEROUS TYPE
OF POSITION TO TAKE. >> BUT THE REAL REASON THAT I'M
HERE TO TALK AGAIN IS I'M STILL VERY CONCERNED ABOUT THE FACT
THAT THIS BOARD IS NOT DOING ITS DUTY IN ORDER TO.
I FEEL CENSURE ONE OF ITS MEMBERS AND INDUCE HER TO
RESIGN BECAUSE SHE'S HOLDING UP DISTRICT NINE.
I SEE THAT EXCUSE ME THE DISTRICT AND I SEE THESE
SUPERVISOR IS ABSENCE. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
ONCE AGAIN. >> NEXT SPEAKER IS PAUSE MY
TIME. IT HASN'T BEGUN.
IS THE SPEAKER'S READY WHILE WE'RE WHILE WE'RE WAITING FOR
THE SPEAKER IS THERE ANY OTHER INDIVIDUAL WHO WOULD LIKE TO
PROVIDE PUBLIC COMMENT WILL BE CLOSING PUBLIC COMMENT AFTER
THE SHOWS IF IT DOESN'T I'M SORRY PLEASE LET ME KNOW WHAT'S
BEING SHOWN ON SCREEN. ALL RIGHT.
OKAY. I'LL TRY.
YEAH. I'M SORRY IF IT'S NOT PERFECT
BEST I CAN. >> ALL RIGHT.
OKAY. HI, MY NAME IS JESSICA PASCOE
ARE AN EXPERT WITNESS AND LEGAL REPRESENTATIVE FOUNDER SINGER
SONGWRITER, COMMUNITY ORGANIZER .
AND SO HERE IS WHAT MY PUBLIC COMMENT IS.
COULD WE VOTE YES FOR A SET OF BILLS FOR 009 TO STOP
HARVESTING ORGANS IN CHINA? THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE ARE WANTING
OUTSIDE CAN WE ALSO VOTE AGAINST YOU KNOW, STREAMLINING
THE CHARTER? >> WE WANT TO PRESERVE THE
CHARTER. IN FACT, WE WANT IT
STRENGTHENED. WE WANT THE ARTS COMMISSION
AND MORE TO ACTUALLY GET MORE ADVOCACY AND MORE PEOPLE ON
THERE BECAUSE WE NEED MORE SERVICES IN OUR DISTRICT RIGHT
NOW IN DISTRICT TEN WE HAVE NO BANKS.
WE HAVE NO APPLE STORE. BUT WHAT WE DO HAVE IS.
OPPORTUNITY I'M GOING TO TRY TO BRING UP MY PHONE HERE FOR A
MINUTE. THERE ARE SOME GRANTS THAT ARE
AVAILABLE ON THE GOVERNMENT WEBSITE FOR THIRD STREET
AND THE BAYVIEW. IF ANYONE WANTS TO OPEN UP A
STOREFRONT THERE. WE'D ALSO LIKE TO EXTEND THIS
TO THE OTHER DISTRICTS INCLUDING DISTRICT FIVE.
WE WANT TO OPEN UP SOME STOREFRONTS AND GET PEOPLE SOME
GRANTS. WE NEED SOME MORE BUSINESSES
IN OUR AREAS. OH I ONLY HAVE 35 SECONDS.
>> SO WHEN I WAS ATTENDING THE YOUTH COMMISSION THEY WANTED
THERE WAS A6I VOTE TO GET US SURE A RIDE SHARE COMPANIES
BIKE SHARE COMPANIES TO GET HELMETS FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
RIDING THE BIKES BECAUSE THEY WANTED TO PREVENT ACCIDENTS.
FIGURE OUT HOW YOU WANT TO VOTE ON THAT COULD BE COSTLY BUT ON
THE OTHER HAND THERE'S ISSUES WITH SANITATION.
BUT IF THERE'S NOTHING TO THERE'S NO COST ON THE
CONSUMER. THIS COULD BE A GOOD IDEA
BECAUSE AGAIN WE DO WANT TO PREVENT BIKE ACCIDENTS.
>> WE KNOW THOSE COSTLY. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
SEEING NO OTHER SPEAKERS, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> ALL RIGHT. PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED.
>> MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE
REFERENCE TO AGENDA PLEASE CALL ITEM 34 THROUGH 40 ITEMS 34
THROUGH 40 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE
REFERENCE. A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED
FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE ANY SUPERVISOR
MAY REQUEST A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE TO GO TO
COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR HUANG LIKE TO SEVER ITEM 39 TO SPEAK ON IT
ITEM 39. GOT IT SUE VISOR DORSEY I'D
LIKE TO SEVER ITEM 34 SORRY 34 AND SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU
PRESIDENT AMENDMENT I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE I'M ADDED AS A
CO-SPONSOR TO NUMBER 37 NUMBER 38 AND ITEM 39 YES YOU'VE BEEN
ADDED. THANK.
>> AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR TO SEVER HER ITEM 37 PLEASE.
AND I'D ALSO LIKE TO BE ADDED TO ITEM 39.
OKAY. >> OKAY.
SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU PRESIDENT.
>> I ALSO WOULD LIKE TO ACT AS A CO-SPONSOR TO A NUMBER 39
STEP. ALL RIGHT.
SO I THINK ITEMS 3437 AND 39 HAVE BEEN SEVERED OFF.
>> YES. SO ITEMS 35, 36, 38 AND 40 CALL
THE ROLL ON THOSE ITEMS. >> SUPERVISOR SOLDER SOLDER I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR HUANG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN I. AMENDMENT I SUPERVISOR MELGAR I
MELGAR I THEIR NINE EYES ALL RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED AND MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM 34 ITEM 34 IS A RESOLUTION TO DECLARE APRIL 24TH 2026 AS
ARBOR DAY IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU PRESIDENT MANDOLIN COLLEAGUES
TODAY WILL BE VOTING ON A RESOLUTION DECLARING APRIL 23RD
24TH 2026 AS ARBOR DAY IN SAN FRANCISCO.
ARBOR DAY IS A REMINDER THAT TREES ARE ONE OF THE SIMPLEST
AND MOST IMPACTFUL INVESTMENTS WE CAN MAKE IN OUR CITY.
THEY IMPROVE AIR QUALITY, REDUCE NOISE, PROVIDE SHADE
AND MAKE OUR NEIGHBORHOODS MORE LIVABLE.
THAT'S ESPECIALLY IMPORTANT IN DENSE NEIGHBORHOODS LIKE THE
SOUTH MARKET AND TENDERLOIN WHERE ACCESS TO GREEN SPACE
AND TREE CANOPY CANOPY CAN HAVE A REAL IMPACT ON QUALITY OF
LIFE. THIS PAST WEEKEND WE SAW THAT
ACTION THAT IN ACTION IN THE SOUTH OF MARKET WHERE
VOLUNTEERS CAME TOGETHER FOR A NEIGHBORHOOD TREE PLANTING DAY.
IT WAS A GREAT EXAMPLE OF THE KIND OF COMMUNITY STEWARDSHIP
THIS RESOLUTION IS MEANT TO UPLIFT.
>> EXPANDING OUR URBAN FOREST IS ABOUT EQUITY AND CLIMATE
RESILIENCE HELPING ADDRESS LONG STANDING DISPARITIES WHILE
REDUCING URBAN HEAT AND SUPPORTING A HEALTHIER
ENVIRONMENT FOR EVERYONE. I WANT TO THANK THE SAN
FRANCISCO DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS, THE SAN FRANCISCO
RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT, THE FRIENDS OF THE
URBAN FOREST AND BOARD PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN WHO JOINED
ME THERE FOR THEIR ONGOING WORK TO PLANT AND CARE FOR TREES
ACROSS OUR CITY. ALSO DESERVING OF RECOGNITION
ARE THE MULTITUDE OF TREE ADVOCATES IN COMMUNITIES
THROUGHOUT SAN FRANCISCO SO THOSE WHO PARTNER WITH OUR CITY
WHO PUSH US TO DO MORE AND WHO CONSISTENTLY SHOW UP TO CARE
FOR AND IMPROVE THEIR NEIGHBORHOODS IN MY DISTRICT
WHICH HAS FAR FEWER TREES THAN WE SHOULD HAVE, I SINGLE OUT
FOR APPRECIATION THE SUMMER WEST NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATION
AND SHAWN OAKLAND, A CONSTITUENT OF MINE WHO HAS
UNDERTAKEN SOME EXCELLENT RESEARCH AND ADVOCACY ON THIS
TOPIC. FINALLY I WANT TO GIVE A SHOUT
OUT TO RYAN ORTIZ WHO SPOKE IN PUBLIC COMMENT.
RYAN IS AN INTERN IN MY OFFICE AND I'M VERY PROUD OF HIM FOR
THE EXCELLENT WORK HE HAS DONE IN RESEARCHING AND PUTTING
TOGETHER THIS RESOLUTION. IT ENCOURAGES SAN FRANCISCANS
TO GET INVOLVED ON ARBOR DAY WHETHER PLANTING A TREE, CARING
FOR ONE OR JUST TAKING TIME TO APPRECIATE THE URBAN FOREST
AROUND US. I HOPE IT WILL HAVE YOUR
SUPPORT. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR DORSEY WITHOUT
WITHOUT I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 37 ITEM
37 IS A RESOLUTION TO MARK THE 111TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE
ARMENIAN GENOCIDE AND DECLARING APRIL 24TH 2026 AS ARMENIAN
GENOCIDE COMMEMORATION DAY IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO. >> SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
THANK YOU AND THANK YOU COLLEAGUES FOR YOUR
CO-SPONSORSHIP OF THIS RESOLUTION COMMEMORATING THE
111TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE AND DECLARING
APRIL 24TH, 2026 AS THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE COMMEMORATION
DAY IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE IS ONE OF THE MOST ATROCIOUS CRIMES
AGAINST HUMANITY RESULTING IN THE MURDER OF OVER 1.5
MILLION ARMENIANS BY THE TURKISH EMPIRE.
>> YET TO THIS DAY THERE CONTINUES TO BE AN OFFICIAL
POLICY OF DENIALISM BY THE GOVERNMENTS OF TURKEY
AND AZERBAIJAN. THE ARMENIAN COMMUNITY IS STILL
FEELING THREATENED IN SAN FRANCISCO AND ALL OVER THE
WORLD. DISTRICT SEVEN IS HOME TO A
LARGE ARMENIAN COMMUNITY AND SEVERAL INSTITUTIONS
IN RECENT YEARS HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> THERE WERE SHOTS FIRED AT THE KAIKOHE ARMENIAN SCHOOL ON
BROTHERHOOD WAY IN MY DISTRICT AND ARSON THAT TOOK PLACE AT ST
GREGORY'S IN DISTRICT TWO AN ARMENIAN CHURCH THAT ALSO HAS A
COMMUNITY CENTER WHICH WAS WHICH HAS STILL NOT BEEN FULLY
REPAIRED TODAY. >> THE CROSS AT THE TOP OF MT.
DAVIDSON IS CONSTANTLY DEFACED WITH HATEFUL GRAFFITI.
OUR PLACES OF REFUGE SHOULD NOT BE PLACES OF FEAR.
WE MUST CONDEMN THESE ACTS. THE ARMENIAN GENOCIDE
COMMEMORATION AT MOUNT DAVIS AT CROSS WILL TAKE PLACE THIS YEAR
ON SUNDAY APRIL 26TH AT 2 P.M.. I ENCOURAGE MY COLLEAGUES TO
ATTEND TO HOLD SPACE WITH A GREATER KARMIC COMMUNITY
IN REMEMBERING THIS TRAGEDY AND RECOGNIZING THE RESILIENCE
OF THE ARMENIAN PEOPLE IN THE ARMENIAN COMMUNITY IN SAN
FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MELGAR. LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> AND MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 39. >> ITEM 39 IS A RESOLUTION TO
HONOR THE LIFE AND LEGACY OF FEATURE RATS AN IMPACT ON THE
FIFTH ANNIVERSARY OF HIS PASSING CONDEMNING VIOLENCE
AGAINST ELDERS AND REAFFIRMING SAN FRANCISCO COMMITS SAN
FRANCISCO'S COMMITMENT TO ELDERS SAFETY, VIOLENCE
PREVENTION, COMMUNITY HEALING AND STANDING AGAINST ANTI-ASIAN
HATE. >> SUPERVISOR WONG.
COLLEAGUES THANK YOU. I'M PROUD TO BRING THIS
RESOLUTION FORWARD TODAY. I WANT TO FIRST THANK THE
RETIREMENT PARTY FAMILY FOR REACHING OUT AND TRUSTING US
WITH THIS RESOLUTION. I'M DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR THE
OPPORTUNITY TO BE HERE AND HONORED GRANDPA OF HIS LIFE
ON BEHALF OF THEIR FAMILY FIVE YEARS AGO ON A JANUARY MORNING
IN 2021, AN 84 YEAR OLD GRANDFATHER NAMED VICENTE
RETIREMENT PARTY LEFT HIS DAUGHTER'S APARTMENT AND THE
VISTA TO TAKE HIS DAILY WALK. HE NEVER CAME HOME.
HE WAS SHOVED TO THE GROUND IN THE UNPROVOKED ATTACK.
HE DIED TWO DAYS LATER FROM HIS INJURIES.
THE RETURN OF PARTY FAMILY CALLED HIM GRANDPA VICTOR.
SO DID THE CITY EVENTUALLY AND SO DID THE COUNTRY.
HE BECAME THE FACE OF A MOVEMENT THAT CAME OUT OF A
MOMENT WHEN ASIAN-AMERICAN ELDERS WERE AFRAID TO WALK
THEIR OWN STREETS. AND WHEN ANTI-ASIAN HATE CRIMES
IN SAN FRANCISCO ROSE 567% IN A SINGLE YEAR, HIS FAMILY HAS
SPENT THE FIVE YEARS SINCE TRUMP OF HIS DEATH REFUSING TO
LET THE GRIEF BE PRIVATE. THEY'VE STOOD AT RALLIES AT
PRESS CONFERENCES AND AT CEREMONIES AND HAVE DONE MORE
FOR THEIR LOVED ONES MEMORY THAN MOST OF US WILL EVER BE
ASKED TO DO. THE RETURN OF FAMILY HAS THEIR
GRATITUDE AND THEY HAVE OUR CONTINUED COMMITMENT.
I BRING THIS RESOLUTION FORWARD AS THE SON OF IMMIGRANTS WHO
GREW UP IN THE SUNSET A NEIGHBORHOOD FULL OF
GRANDPARENTS WHO TAKE THE SAME MORNING WALKS WHICH I TOOK
EVERY ASIAN-AMERICAN FAMILY IN THIS CITY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
HAPPENED TO GRANDPA EACH YEAR BECAUSE EVERY ASIAN AMERICAN
FAMILY SEES THEIR OWN LOVED ONES IN HIM.
>> GRANDPA WHICH BECAME SOMETHING SO MUCH LARGER
INSPIRED A MOVEMENT INSPIRED ME AND SO MANY OTHER YOUNG PEOPLE
TO GET INVOLVED IN THE COMMUNITIES IN THE NAME OF
SAFETY FOR SENIORS. >> WHAT WE ARE SEEING TODAY IS
WHAT WE SHOULD BE SAYING EVERY DAY.
OUR ELDERS DESERVE TO MOVE THROUGH THIS CITY WITHOUT FEAR
VIOLENCE AGAINST THE OLDEST AND MOST VULNERABLE AMONG US IS
AN ASSAULT ON WHO WE ARE AS A CITY.
THIS RESOLUTION HONORS EACH HIS LIFE.
IT COMMITS SAN FRANCISCO TO ELDER SAFETY VIOLENCE
PREVENTION AND COMMUNITY HEALING.
HE ASKS OUR CITY DEPARTMENTS OUR PUBLIC SAFETY AGENCIES
AND OUR EDUCATORS TO TEACH AND ACT WITH RESPECT FOR ELDERS
AND FOR THE COMMUNITIES THAT HAVE BEEN MOST TARGETED.
I WANT TO THANK MY CO SPONSORS SUPERVISORS CHERYL SAUTER,
MAILMAN DORSEY WALTON MAHMOOD MELGAR AND CHEN FOR JOINING ME
IN THIS. TO TRULY HONOR HIS LIFE IS NOT
ONLY TO REMEMBER BUT TO ACT TO BUILD A CITY WHERE EVERY ELDER
IS PROTECTED, RESPECTED AND ABLE TO MOVE THROUGH THEIR
COMMUNITY WITHOUT FEAR. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR HUANG. WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, DO WE HAVE ANY
IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS? >> WE HAVE NO IMPERATIVE TO
AGENDA ITEMS TODAY. >> COULD YOU PLEASE READ THE
IN MEMORIAM? YES.
TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE
FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS. ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WANG
FOR THE LATE MISS HONG CHING PAUL ANG AND ON BEHALF OF
SUPERVISORS MELGAR CHEN IN WALTON AND THE ENTIRE BOARD
FOR THE LATE REVEREND ROLAND GORDON.
>> AND I BELIEVE THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA, MADAM
CLERK. >> DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER
BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY? THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR
TODAY. >> THEN WE ARE ADJOURNED